<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>RIP on Rusland 1</title>
    <link>/en/trefwoorden/rip/</link>
    <description>Recent content in RIP on Rusland 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/trefwoorden/rip/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mark Bernes – Dark Is the Night (Тёмная ночь)</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20201110-mark-bernes-donker-de-nacht/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20201110-mark-bernes-donker-de-nacht/</guid>
      <description>Lyrics and explanation The song has its own page on Wikipedia. See Dark Is the Night (Soviet song) and the Russian version. Check Soundtimes.ru for a brief history and interesting facts. Definitely watch Songs from the film &amp;ldquo;Two Soldiers&amp;rdquo; performed by Mark Bernes (Первая Столица, 2015, 9 m).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yanka Dyagileva </title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20200812-yanka-dyagileva/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20200812-yanka-dyagileva/</guid>
      <description>She was never able to record anything with professional sound quality, but somehow, her music doesn’t seem to suffer for it—in fact, it almost seems like it was made for this rawness. It was difficult to choose just three tracks, so there are seven.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alone on the Road (Выхожу один я на дорогу)</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20200502-alleen-op-weg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20200502-alleen-op-weg/</guid>
      <description>Poem and Text The text of Выхожу один я на дорогу can be found on retroportal.ru. You can also find the text with translations on Lyricstranslate – including Dutch translations, in four versions. For an analysis of the poem, watch the video below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maya Kristalinskaya – Tenderness</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20200218-maya-kristalinskaya-tederheid/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20200218-maya-kristalinskaya-tederheid/</guid>
      <description>Film Known, among other things, for this film scene (starting at 1:30 min), from Три тополя на Плющихе or Three Poplars in Plyushchikha (1967). Definitely watch these three minutes from that film, featuring music by La Kristalinskaya.
Performances The song, written in 1965 by Александра Пахмутова (Aleksandra Pakhmutova), has been performed many times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Konstantin Stupin – When I Died</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/190613-konstantin-stupin-toen-ik-stierf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/190613-konstantin-stupin-toen-ik-stierf/</guid>
      <description>Когда я умер взорвалось солнце: when I died, the sun exploded. And сметая звезды: swept away the stars.
Online sources that reveal the lyrics contradict each other on details. See &amp;amp; compare, for example, Tekstovoi.ru and – with chords as a bonus – MyChords.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
