<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cities and country on Rusland 1</title>
    <link>/en/land_en_volk_onderwerpen/cities-and-country/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cities and country on Rusland 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/land_en_volk_onderwerpen/cities-and-country/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Flag and Emblem (2/2): Saint George and the Eagle</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20210308-wapen_van_rusland/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20210308-wapen_van_rusland/</guid>
      <description>Eagle East versus West or symbol of national schizophrenia, it’s not about that. The two-headed eagle (also seen in Albania, Serbia, and Montenegro) was used in the Byzantine Empire (and even earlier) and expresses unity rather than contradiction or division.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flag and Emblem (1/2): Russian Flag</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20210228-russische-vlag/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20210228-russische-vlag/</guid>
      <description>Meaning There are several interpretations regarding the reasoning behind this tricolor. One says white stands for God, blue for the tsar or king, and red for the land and people. More commonly, the colors are linked to noble qualities: white for purity, blue for loyalty, red for courage, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mother of God on the Moat: St. Basil’s Cathedral</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20210109-basiliuskathedraal-saint-basils-cathedral/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20210109-basiliuskathedraal-saint-basils-cathedral/</guid>
      <description>Ivan IV Built to commemorate the Conquest of Kazan on the orders of Ivan IV (1530-1584), better known as the Terrible or Грозный. While the name translates to &amp;ldquo;terrible,&amp;rdquo; it&amp;rsquo;s a bit exaggerated – as a character sketch, it&amp;rsquo;s still mild.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There to find: In Russia (в России)</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20201225-in-rusland-in-russia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20201225-in-rusland-in-russia/</guid>
      <description>An exploration Well, Vincent Urban, Max Neumeier and Tim Höddinghaus are not just occasional filmmakers with a simple drone and camera. In Russia – в России is also (as described on YouTube, see there for more) ‘an exploration of all the different lenses, viewpoints, and expectations one can apply in a travel film’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demography (2/2): Russia’s Many Leavers</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20201221-demografie-2-ruslands-vele-vertrekkers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20201221-demografie-2-ruslands-vele-vertrekkers/</guid>
      <description>Happiness Russia ranks 68th in the World Happiness Report (read or download via here), with a barely passing score of 5.6 based on factors like prosperity, social connection, life expectancy, and freedom of choice. Even Pakistan ranks higher. Good news for Russians is that their happiness is practically around the corner: neighboring Finland is number 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demographics (1/2): Russia’s Shrinking Population</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20201217-demografie-1-ruslands-krimpende-bevolking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20201217-demografie-1-ruslands-krimpende-bevolking/</guid>
      <description>Looking ahead to 2060 and 2100 in By 2060, this country will have the world&amp;rsquo;s largest population (World Economic Forum) and These will be the 10 largest countries by population in 2100 (Business Insider, 2019) – though an article on Russia’s demographics should naturally begin with the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Motherland Calls! Mother of all Statues</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20201120-moederland-roept-moeder-aller-standbeelden/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20201120-moederland-roept-moeder-aller-standbeelden/</guid>
      <description>Facts and Figures More facts and figures about The Motherland Calls (also known as Mother Russia) can be found on Wikipedia in English, Dutch, and Russian. Also see The Motherland Calls – Mother Russia (Historiek.net) and «Родина-мать зовет!» 10 Facts about the Monument (Culture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dead or Reviving: Russian Villages</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20200727-dood-of-herlevend-russische-dorpen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20200727-dood-of-herlevend-russische-dorpen/</guid>
      <description>Presented in order of release.
Lost A somber depiction of the потерянное богатство страны, the lost wealth of the nation. ‘How Russia is dying.’ Subtitles available in settings.
Как погибает Россия. Разруха, воровство и смерть в русской деревне (Varlamov, 16-04-2020, 48 m)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cold, Colder, Coldest: Oymyakon</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20200321-ojmjakon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20200321-ojmjakon/</guid>
      <description>There are only (or despite that, still) about 500 souls living there; more of a village than a city. But &amp;lsquo;World’s coldest village or Coldest city in the world – it is очень холодно (very cold) there. Read/watch and shiver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Size Matters</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20190412-size-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20190412-size-matters/</guid>
      <description>Largest in the whole world First, try to understand the country, or at least attempt to. That&amp;rsquo;s where you start – but that’s quite the task. Of all the countries in the world (about 200), Россия (in terms of area) is by far the largest, and it is not easily comprehended.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
