<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>letters on Rusland 1</title>
    <link>/en/taal_onderwerpen/letters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in letters on Rusland 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/taal_onderwerpen/letters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wrong Cyrillic</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20210319-fout_cyrillisch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20210319-fout_cyrillisch/</guid>
      <description>Misuse of Cyrillic The letter Я (also the word for I) has nothing to do with an R. And the И/и is an I/i, not an N/n. If it is used that way, then disasters like Яussiaи are the consequences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>O and A: Tolstoy, Bolshoi and krakadil Gena</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20210311-o_en_a_tolstoj_bolshoi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20210311-o_en_a_tolstoj_bolshoi/</guid>
      <description>Oh and ah The o is the most common letter in Russian (as mentioned in Paste Sounds). Were all those o&amp;rsquo;s to have an o sound, the whole language would have changed sound. Now it has been determined that an unstressed o (usually) sounds like an a, and that was a good idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ш and щ: Spot the Differences</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20201227-zoek-de-verschillen-sha-en-sshha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20201227-zoek-de-verschillen-sha-en-sshha/</guid>
      <description>Sound For what descriptions of sounds are worth: Wikipedia compares ш to ‘sh in shop’ and ‘ch in machine,’ but when it comes to щ, it hits a dead end: ‘Dutch has no words with this sound.’ The English Wikipedia entry for shcha/щ isn’t much help either: ‘it represents the voiceless alveolo-palatal fricative /ɕ(ː)/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The letter ы</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20200826-de-letter-bi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20200826-de-letter-bi/</guid>
      <description>Sounds Like An indescribable sound, indeed. But people have tried. Wikipedia loosely describes it as “like the u in bunker” (which is far off). Wikibooks says it’s somewhere between &amp;ldquo;u&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;j&amp;rdquo;, while Russisch in Rusland compares it to something between &amp;ldquo;u&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;i&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The letter Ё</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20200219-de-letter-e/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20200219-de-letter-e/</guid>
      <description>Yo The sound isn’t hard. It’s like the Yo in York, says the (English) Wikipedia. The Dutch version compares it to the jo in jokken (to fib). Russian sources often give examples like ёжик (jozhik, hedgehog) or ёлка (yolka, Christmas tree).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alphabet Music</title>
      <link>/en/taal/190420-alfabetmuziek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/190420-alfabetmuziek/</guid>
      <description>More Alphabet Song (Cyrillic) (World With Nathalie, 2018) The russian alphabet song with English subtitles (Apprendre le russe, 2015, 2 m) Cyrillic Alphabet Song (Learn with me, 2015) Sing Russian Alphabet Song (Learn Russian Language, 2013) This one is fun, with singing by Fedor Derkach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyrillic</title>
      <link>/en/taal/190420-cyrillisch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/190420-cyrillisch/</guid>
      <description>Three short clips (more under the videos) about the history of Cyrillic.
Cyril and Slavic Christianity – Christian History Made Easy (Rose Publishing, 2012, 2 m)
Cyril and Methodices (Museum of the Bible, 2017, 1 m)
The creation of Cyrillic Script / История за кирилицата (Elektrick Me, 2018, 3 m)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Piece of Cake: Russian Alphabet</title>
      <link>/en/taal/190412-abctje/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/190412-abctje/</guid>
      <description>Apps Starting simple is recommended. For Android users: Russian alphabet for kids is great for beginners and looks cheerful. You’ll also learn some basic words right away. Russian Alphabet is less about cheerfulness but is clear and practical. Some example words are (too) difficult for beginners.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
