<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cases on Rusland 1</title>
    <link>/en/taal_onderwerpen/cases/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cases on Rusland 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/taal_onderwerpen/cases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SIXTH NOUN: LOCATIVE/PREPOSITIONAL</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20240601_zesde_naamval__locatief_prepositional/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20240601_zesde_naamval__locatief_prepositional/</guid>
      <description>Here (only) about usage; conjugations in a subsequent section, though you will inevitably encounter them below. Location The main use of the sixth noun is to designate a place - the name “locative” already indicates it, most other uses flow from it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fifth Case: Instrumental</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20210113-vijfde-naamval-instrumentalis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20210113-vijfde-naamval-instrumentalis/</guid>
      <description>Usage Professions We say: he works as a lawyer, or: he is a lawyer. Russian can do that without &amp;ldquo;as&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;is.&amp;rdquo; Кем он работает = what does he work as, what is his profession. Кто (who) in the instrumental case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fourth Case: Accusative</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20201125-vierde-naamval-accusatief/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20201125-vierde-naamval-accusatief/</guid>
      <description>Usage Direct Object The fourth case, or accusative, is used when something happens to someone or something. In the sentence, it acts as the direct object. For example: &amp;ldquo;I buy a magazine, I read the newspaper.&amp;rdquo; Magazine and newspaper are direct objects (and take the accusative case) because they are being bought or read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Third Case: Dative</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20200818-derde-naamval-datief/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20200818-derde-naamval-datief/</guid>
      <description>Use дательный падеж when someone or something receives something. Here&amp;rsquo;s how and when to use it.
Usage You use дательный падеж in the following situations.
Indirect Object When something is given or directed at someone. Often, the recipient is a person, and the dative case takes over the role of &amp;ldquo;to&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second Case: Genitive</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20200419-tweede-naamval-genitief/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20200419-tweede-naamval-genitief/</guid>
      <description>Usage Of the The genitive is a &amp;lsquo;of the&amp;rsquo; (or &amp;lsquo;of the&amp;rsquo;) case. Where Dutch uses compound words (schoonheidssalon, wereldkampioenschap) and English uses separate words (beauty salon, world championship), Russian uses the second case for such things. Thus, you get салон красоты (salon of beauty) and чемпионат мира (championship of the world).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nominative Case: именительный падеж</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20200417-eerste-naamval-nominatief/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20200417-eerste-naamval-nominatief/</guid>
      <description>What or who The nominative case is the unmodified or default form of a word. If nothing is being done to it in the sentence, you don’t need to do anything either.*)
This is my car, the book is thick: машина and книга stay as they are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Six Cases</title>
      <link>/en/taal/200216-zes-naamvallen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/200216-zes-naamvallen/</guid>
      <description>The Six Cases Nominative, genitive, dative, accusative, instrumental, and locative. The six Russian grammatical cases (in English: cases, in Russian падежи) affect words, names, numbers—basically everything, and all the time.
Case / Case Name Падеж nominative / nominative имени́тельный genitive / genitive роди́тельный dative / dative да́тельный accusative / accusative вини́тельный instrumental / instrumental твори́тельный locative / prepositional предло́жный (Abbreviations: Им, Рд, Дт, Вн, Тв, Пр – sometimes a single letter is used)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
