<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Putin on Rusland 1</title>
    <link>/en/trefwoorden/putin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Putin on Rusland 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/trefwoorden/putin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Punk against Putin: Criminal State – Путин</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/criminal-state-putin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/criminal-state-putin/</guid>
      <description>Almost all Russians love their country, but not all love their leader(s). Especially not that one. Criminal State (est. 2010) makes it clear. Lyrics below, with translation here. Explicit lyrics.
Путин (2014) We want to live freely so that no one hinders us so that all scum dies the f*** out the cop and politician suck it punks don&amp;rsquo;t love Putin they reject all the bulls*** governments can f*** off all politicians to prison</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tucker Carlson and Vladimir Putin</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20240606_tucker_carlson_en_vladmir_poetin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20240606_tucker_carlson_en_vladmir_poetin/</guid>
      <description>Rurik About a quarter of the more than two-hour interview was devoted to answering the first question, or rather, to Putin’s opening monologue. It began in 862 with Prince Rurik; from there, returning to the present was quite the journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OPERATION WAR</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20240507-operatie_oorlog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20240507-operatie_oorlog/</guid>
      <description>Speech Putin gave a speech (see also here and here) and, one assumes, believed in a quick victory. It turned into a disaster for everyone, and over two years later, the likelihood of terrible escalation seems more realistic than that of a quick end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian New Year (Новый год) and the First Encounter</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20201231-russisch-nieuwjaar-novy-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20201231-russisch-nieuwjaar-novy-god/</guid>
      <description>Begin = continuation Linked to New Year is a Russian saying (in the realm of superstition) that can sound both motivating and ominous. Как встретишь Новый год (How you begin/meet the New Year), так его и проведёшь (is how it will go).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wegmans? The Name Putin and the Word путь</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20201214-de-naam-poetin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20201214-de-naam-poetin/</guid>
      <description>Mr. Wegmans You can listen to it here. Around 2:54, you’ll hear that the name probably comes from путь (put), meaning &amp;lsquo;way&amp;rsquo; (or &amp;lsquo;path&amp;rsquo;). Ms. Rutten sticks to Wegmans and doesn’t say mister. She does mention it&amp;rsquo;s a cute name, but someone interrupts her at that point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russia and LGBT etc.</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20201204-rusland-en-lgbt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20201204-rusland-en-lgbt/</guid>
      <description>Legislation Reactions from that time to the law in Russia&amp;rsquo;s anti-gay law (The Economist, 2013, 8 m) and Putin signs law banning homosexual ‘propaganda’ (Euronews, 2013, 1 m). See also Russia: ‘Gay propaganda’ law remains in place, but complaints against it continue (CRIN).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Russian with Vladimir Putin (2/2)</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20200515-leer-russisch-met-poetin-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20200515-leer-russisch-met-poetin-2/</guid>
      <description>With a questioner who might also work for a school newspaper and a rather admiring boyish look. Anna introduces it with: “an interview with a person about whom everyone seems to have an opinion, positive or negative.” And concludes with: “and we will refrain from any political comments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Russian with Vladimir Putin (1/2)</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20200420-leer-russisch-met-poetin-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20200420-leer-russisch-met-poetin-1/</guid>
      <description>From jokes to weapons Several options are available, both in terms of channels and topics. As part of the Russian Listening Test (Playlist), Anastasia Semina (Russian with Anastasia) created Putin talks about his hobbies. Путин говорит о своих хобби (2017, 2 m) and Vladimir Putin makes jokes at the press conference (2016, 3 m).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Putin 3x</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20190420-poetin-3x/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20190420-poetin-3x/</guid>
      <description>Three portraits Putin viewed from different angles: three portraits from 2017-2018. Two are long (American and British), one is very long (Russian, with subtitles). Links to shorter clips are at the bottom.
The Power of Putin – BBC Documentary (Astrobum, 2017, 43 m)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
