<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>words on Rusland 1</title>
    <link>/en/taal_onderwerpen/words/</link>
    <description>Recent content in words on Rusland 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/taal_onderwerpen/words/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>O and A: Tolstoy, Bolshoi and krakadil Gena</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20210311-o_en_a_tolstoj_bolshoi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20210311-o_en_a_tolstoj_bolshoi/</guid>
      <description>Oh and ah The o is the most common letter in Russian (as mentioned in Paste Sounds). Were all those o&amp;rsquo;s to have an o sound, the whole language would have changed sound. Now it has been determined that an unstressed o (usually) sounds like an a, and that was a good idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stress (Ударение)</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20210304-klemtoon-in-russisch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20210304-klemtoon-in-russisch/</guid>
      <description>Interests Catalógus or catálogus? The latter is correct (traceable to the Greek), but no one looks strangely if you say catalógus. In Russian, emphasis is more important. It can determine both the pronunciation of a word (an stressed syllable sometimes sounds very different from an unstressed one) and its spelling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian Antonyms (антонимы)</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20201223-russische-antoniemen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20201223-russische-antoniemen/</guid>
      <description>Negation Often, if you don’t know the antonym of an adjective, it&amp;rsquo;s not a big problem. Just add не (not) in front of it, and you&amp;rsquo;re done. This is similar to the English prefixes &amp;ldquo;un-&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;in-&amp;rdquo;: unattractive, unwise, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian Adjectives (Прилагательные)</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20201219-russische-bijvoeglijk-naamwoorden/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20201219-russische-bijvoeglijk-naamwoorden/</guid>
      <description>Declensions Flexible First, you need to know how to decline them. Russian adjectives are flexible: they adapt to the gender and number of the noun they modify. New text, new idea, new morning, new plans: новый текст (m.), новая идея (f.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian Abbreviations, Truncations, and Acronyms</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20201210-russische-afkortingen-inkortingen-acroniemen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20201210-russische-afkortingen-inkortingen-acroniemen/</guid>
      <description>и т.д. etc. Starting with a common abbreviation (аббревиатура) that you often use at the end. и т.д. (note the space after и) = etc., as it stands for и так далее, meaning &amp;ldquo;and so on&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;and so forth&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tongue Twisters (1/2): Long Words and Pronunciation Practice Materials</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20201202-tongbrekers-1-lange-woorden/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20201202-tongbrekers-1-lange-woorden/</guid>
      <description>Difficult words This is straightforward: see for yourself if these are hard.
The Hardest Russian Words to Pronounce (Russian with Tatiana, 2019, 7 m) Pronouncing Hardest Russian Words (Living Life With The Shirins, 2019, 11 m) 10 Most Difficult Russian Words (Russian with Nastya, 2019, 6 m), from the same channel: 10 Russian Words That You Pronounce Incorrectly (2019, 5 m) The 10 Hardest Russian Words to Pronounce (Tsar Experience, 2018, 6 m) The 10 Hardest Russian Words to Pronounce (Conor Clyne, 2018, 6 m) Learn the Top 10 Hardest Russian Words to Pronounce (RussianPod101, 2015, 5 m) Long words Russian words are, on average, just a bit longer than Dutch ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian Calendar Words: Months and Days</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20201118-russische-kalenderwoorden-maanden-en-dagen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20201118-russische-kalenderwoorden-maanden-en-dagen/</guid>
      <description>January–December Let’s start with the months of the year. They&amp;rsquo;re not particularly exciting—no more interesting than the names you&amp;rsquo;re used to. The origins are the same: Roman gods and goddesses (January, March, May, June), words (February, April), emperors (July, August), and numbers (September through December).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Words ending in ь</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20200716-woorden-eindigend-op-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20200716-woorden-eindigend-op-b/</guid>
      <description>Masculine A word ending in ь is masculine in the following cases:
Natural gender Words that refer to a man are grammatically masculine. Think of царь (tsar), король (king), зять (son-in-law), and парень (boy, boyfriend, young man).
Calendar months All months in Russian are masculine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questions and Question Words</title>
      <link>/en/taal/200229-vraagwoorden/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/200229-vraagwoorden/</guid>
      <description>How, what, where, etc. If you want to ask when or how he&amp;rsquo;s going, what he&amp;rsquo;s studying, or which university he’s attending, of course, you’ll need question words. These are also not difficult.
Here are the most important ones:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Pronouns</title>
      <link>/en/taal/200224-persoonlijk-voornaamwoord/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/200224-persoonlijk-voornaamwoord/</guid>
      <description>The forms of the second and fourth cases (genitive and accusative) are even identical.
именительный родительный дательный винительный творительный предложный я меня мне меня мной (обо) мне ты тебя тебе тебя тобой (о) тебе он/оно его ему его им (о) нём она её ей её ей (о) ней мы нас нам нас нами (о) нас вы вас вам вас вами (о) вас они их им их ими (о) них Russian Personal Pronouns – Nominative Case (Learn Russian Now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masculine, Feminine, Neuter</title>
      <link>/en/taal/190611-mannelijk-vrouwelijk-onzijdig/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/190611-mannelijk-vrouwelijk-onzijdig/</guid>
      <description>Exceptions For every rule, there’s an exception. имя (name) and время (time) are neuter, кофе (coffee) is masculine, and there are more examples like these. And if a word ends in ь (мягкий знак, the soft sign), it can be either masculine or feminine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vocabulary</title>
      <link>/en/taal/190422-woordenschat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/190422-woordenschat/</guid>
      <description>With love – here are clips (and resources) to help you learn Russian words and build your vocabulary.
Reading First Words Short words that are easy to follow, with pictures included. Да, нет, кот (yes, no, cat): if this is too simple, here is part 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gluing Sounds</title>
      <link>/en/taal/190421-klanken-plakken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/190421-klanken-plakken/</guid>
      <description>From Letters to Words The first step in Russian – learning the alphabet – is already a big step forward. Once you know the letters and their sounds, you can immediately read and pronounce a lot. You just glue the sounds together and try not to stumble.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
