<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Boost Your Russian on Rusland 1</title>
    <link>/en/trefwoorden/boost-your-russian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Boost Your Russian on Rusland 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/trefwoorden/boost-your-russian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learn Russian with Interviews</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20210213-russisch-leren-met-interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20210213-russisch-leren-met-interviews/</guid>
      <description>Viktor Tsoi The series of interviews by Boost Your Russian is modest in scope but features great names, with bilingual subtitles. For instance, Viktor Tsoi (or Цой), shortly after a viewing of the film Игла (The Needle, 1988). Watch it on YouTube, starring Shocking Blue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spoken and Informal Language (разговорный язык)</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20210120-russische-spreektaal-russisch-informeel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20210120-russische-spreektaal-russisch-informeel/</guid>
      <description>This is about spoken and informal language, almost a language in itself. Previously presented as the safe side of slang, looking forward to the part that must follow.
How Russians really speak Russian? Slang, Stress, Reductions (Russian With Max, 2019, 15 mins)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tongue Twisters (1/2): Long Words and Pronunciation Practice Materials</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20201202-tongbrekers-1-lange-woorden/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20201202-tongbrekers-1-lange-woorden/</guid>
      <description>Difficult words This is straightforward: see for yourself if these are hard.
The Hardest Russian Words to Pronounce (Russian with Tatiana, 2019, 7 m) Pronouncing Hardest Russian Words (Living Life With The Shirins, 2019, 11 m) 10 Most Difficult Russian Words (Russian with Nastya, 2019, 6 m), from the same channel: 10 Russian Words That You Pronounce Incorrectly (2019, 5 m) The 10 Hardest Russian Words to Pronounce (Tsar Experience, 2018, 6 m) The 10 Hardest Russian Words to Pronounce (Conor Clyne, 2018, 6 m) Learn the Top 10 Hardest Russian Words to Pronounce (RussianPod101, 2015, 5 m) Long words Russian words are, on average, just a bit longer than Dutch ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Russian with Films (1)</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20201019-russisch-leren-met-films-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20201019-russisch-leren-met-films-1/</guid>
      <description>Short Films with Subtitles Short films require little time or effort. The R1 playlist Short Movies collects (and continues to add) short films with subtitles. Almost everything is under half an hour; the shortest, Мужика хочу, is just 1 minute and 20 seconds, while Не повезло / Bad Luck is a rare 47-minute exception.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Russian with Vladimir Putin (1/2)</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20200420-leer-russisch-met-poetin-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20200420-leer-russisch-met-poetin-1/</guid>
      <description>From jokes to weapons Several options are available, both in terms of channels and topics. As part of the Russian Listening Test (Playlist), Anastasia Semina (Russian with Anastasia) created Putin talks about his hobbies. Путин говорит о своих хобби (2017, 2 m) and Vladimir Putin makes jokes at the press conference (2016, 3 m).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentences for Beginners</title>
      <link>/en/taal/190526-zinnen-voor-beginners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/190526-zinnen-voor-beginners/</guid>
      <description>Top 10 Words for Connecting Thoughts in Russian (RussianPod101, 2017, 4 m)
From the same channel:
150 Most Common Phrases in Russian (2019, 25 m) 100 Phrases Every Russian Beginner Must-Know (2018, 36 m) Top 25 Must-Know Russian Phrases (2015, 8 m) Learn the Top 10 Must-Know Russian Lines You Need for Introducing Yourself (2015, 5 m) Top Must-Know Expressions for Agreeing and Disagreeing (2017, 5 m) Simple Phrases</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
