<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>lyric video on Rusland 1</title>
    <link>/en/trefwoorden/lyric-video/</link>
    <description>Recent content in lyric video on Rusland 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/trefwoorden/lyric-video/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Retuses 3x</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20240701-the_retuses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20240701-the_retuses/</guid>
      <description>Омут Title and opening track of the latest (?) release by The Retuses, in 2019. Lyrics Lyrics with translation
Уходи Lyrics Chords Live in Kiev (2016)
Шаганэ From the talk show Профилактика, 27-01-2012
Lyrics Lyric video Live in Moscow (2012)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nina Brodskaya – January Storm</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20210131-nina-brodskaya-zvenit-yanvarskaya-vyuga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20210131-nina-brodskaya-zvenit-yanvarskaya-vyuga/</guid>
      <description>Not easy (нелегко), not easy to love on this planet (нелегко полюбить на ней).
Passing Each Other By January’s snowstorm rings (звенит январская вьюга) and the rain lashes down hard (и ливни хлещут упруго). Stars race in circles (звёзды мчатся по кругу) and the city noise (шумят города).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Грязь – People Hatred (Я ненавижу людей)</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20210121-gryaz-mensenhaat-i-hate-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20210121-gryaz-mensenhaat-i-hate-people/</guid>
      <description>Hating and Drowning Hating (ненавидеть) is a transitive verb – being hated does something to a person – and is therefore typically in the accusative case. But here, it’s the genitive (plural genitive) because, like it or not, people are living beings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Muslim Magomajev and Big Children&#39;s Choir – New Day</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20210101-muslim-magomajev-groot-kinderkoor-nieuwe-dag/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20210101-muslim-magomajev-groot-kinderkoor-nieuwe-dag/</guid>
      <description>Blue and Red Lyrics (see here) by Nikolai Dobronravov (= Николай Добронравов, 1928). Music by Aleksandra Pakhmutova (= Александра Пахмутова, 1929). Also see Наша Родина – революция (rline.tv, 2017).
Новый день берёт своё начало, The new day takes its start На бескрайних улицах Москвы.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Окружающий Мир – Dance with Me (Танцуй Со Мной)</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20201224-okruzhayushchiy-mir-ten-dans/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20201224-okruzhayushchiy-mir-ten-dans/</guid>
      <description>Lyrics available on Lyricstranslate and in the second video below. Minor corrections have been made in the lyrics at the bottom.
Танцуй со мной (Dance with Me) Slow cigarette smoke Spreads everywhere And I&amp;rsquo;m walking my girlfriend home We drank all night Danced all evening We just wanted To feel lighter together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Louna 3x</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20201201-louna-3x/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20201201-louna-3x/</guid>
      <description>Beginning of a new circle Louna has a new album (October 2020), Начало нового круга (Beginning of a New Circle). It includes Станем стеной, Кто мы? (with Anacondaz), Из этих стен (recorded during the pandemic), and this Сигнал в пустоте (Signal in the Void).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molchat Doma (Молчат Дома) </title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20201117-molchat-doma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20201117-molchat-doma/</guid>
      <description>Molchat Doma x Ploho The link with Ploho is often made. Both bands maintain friendly relations and, in 2019, recorded По краю острова together (lyrics, lyrics with translation). See also An Introduction to Russian Post-Punk with Ploho and Molchat Doma (Post-punk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volodya Kotlyarov &amp; PornoFilms – It Will Pass (Это пройдёт)</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20200722-volodya-kotlyarov-pornofilmy-gaat-voorbij/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20200722-volodya-kotlyarov-pornofilmy-gaat-voorbij/</guid>
      <description>I/We Ivan Golunov For more background and to provide Volodya with more context: Golunov was supported with (and on) the joint front page of three newspapers. Я/Мы Иван Голунов, by Vedomosti, Kommersant, and RBK.
See Russian journalist freed after fierce protests (Trouw, 10-06-2019) and Russian newspapers jointly support arrested colleague (Villamedia, 11-06-2019).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Тараканы! 3x</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20200720-tarakany-3x/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20200720-tarakany-3x/</guid>
      <description>Engagement Lyrically and thematically, Тараканы! is your classic punk(rock) band. Watch and listen to Дезертир из армии зла (Deserter from the army of evil, 2019), Ни рыбы, ни мяса (Neither fish nor fowl, 2018), Я не верю (I don&amp;rsquo;t believe), Что я могу изменить?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animal ДжаZ – Three Stripes</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/190425-animal-%D0%B4%D0%B6%D0%B0z-drie-strepen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/190425-animal-%D0%B4%D0%B6%D0%B0z-drie-strepen/</guid>
      <description>Jeans and Sneakers Джинсы порезаны: jeans cut. Лето: summer. Три полоски на кедах: three stripes on sneakers. Под теплым дождем: in the warm rain. There is also a lyrics version, a performance with Amatory, and one with Alai Oli.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
