<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>documentary on Rusland 1</title>
    <link>/en/land_en_volk_onderwerpen/documentary/</link>
    <description>Recent content in documentary on Rusland 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/land_en_volk_onderwerpen/documentary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hidden treasures: Kladmen (The Dropman)</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20210216-kladmen-the-dropman/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20210216-kladmen-the-dropman/</guid>
      <description>Searching and finding The kladman often has to search as well. For suitable and always new places and ways to hide the goods. In such a way that they can be found by those looking, without being seen by those who don’t know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There to find: In Russia (в России)</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20201225-in-rusland-in-russia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20201225-in-rusland-in-russia/</guid>
      <description>An exploration Well, Vincent Urban, Max Neumeier and Tim Höddinghaus are not just occasional filmmakers with a simple drone and camera. In Russia – в России is also (as described on YouTube, see there for more) ‘an exploration of all the different lenses, viewpoints, and expectations one can apply in a travel film’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian Lives (The Russians &amp; Living in Russia)</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20201124-russische-levens-the-russians-living-in-russia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20201124-russische-levens-the-russians-living-in-russia/</guid>
      <description>The Russians 2 x For the German broadcaster DW, Juri Rescheto (Twitter, profile) traveled through Russia to create the documentary described above. The lives of ordinary Russians, in two parts, titled The Russians – an intimate journey through Russia (2020, 2 x 42 m).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love Love Love: all you need is Ljoebov</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20201106-all-you-need-is-ljoebov/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20201106-all-you-need-is-ljoebov/</guid>
      <description>By Sandhya Daisy Sundaram IMDb, Vimeo
That &amp;lsquo;Sundance-winning&amp;rsquo; refers to this award at a Sundance Institute. There is also a short (2 m) Making Of.
Read: ‘Love. Love. Love.’ in Russian winters (Russia Beyond, 2014).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boris Ryzhy (1974-2001)</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20200724-boris-ryzhy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20200724-boris-ryzhy/</guid>
      <description>Documentary and Portrait More about Ryzhy&amp;rsquo;s life (and the reasons behind his early death) in the documentary by Aliona van der Horst (2009, 59 m). Introduction (2 m) below (with music by Beirut); see also this one (1 m).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vinyl in Russia (and X-rays in the USSR)</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20200716-vinyl-in-rusland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20200716-vinyl-in-rusland/</guid>
      <description>Trailers The name of this trailer is aptly explained, Рок на костях = rock on the bones. No subtitles, and not very inviting. There&amp;rsquo;s also a Новый Трейлер (new trailer) and The Needle in my Ribs (an older one). Music history It’s best to watch the entire documentary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yury Dud’s Kolyma</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20200712-yury-duds-kolyma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20200712-yury-duds-kolyma/</guid>
      <description>Reviews More at New Russian Documentary Brings the Horrors of the Gulag to the YouTube Generation (Alexey Kovalev, tol.org 2019) and articles on Johnson’s Russia List and vsem.ru. Review by Veniamin Zima (a historian) on realnoevremya.com, in English and/or Russian.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cold, Colder, Coldest: Oymyakon</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20200321-ojmjakon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20200321-ojmjakon/</guid>
      <description>There are only (or despite that, still) about 500 souls living there; more of a village than a city. But &amp;lsquo;World’s coldest village or Coldest city in the world – it is очень холодно (very cold) there. Read/watch and shiver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian Tattoo Tour</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/200215-russian-tattoo-tour/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/200215-russian-tattoo-tour/</guid>
      <description>2071, 21 min, English subtitled. More on (and also available via) The Russian Tattoo Tour (In Russia).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian Design</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20190422-russen-en-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20190422-russen-en-design/</guid>
      <description>Documentary by Sergey Shanovich (Сергей Шанович), Shandesign. Russian spoken, English subtitled, 53 min, from 2016. Short introduction here.
100 Years of Design Twenty designers and design collectives (RU) discuss the (international) design that has influenced them. Yury Gordon, Denis Bashev, Maxi Shilov, Stas Aki, Oleg Pashenko, Anton Schnaider (and others) on Bauhaus, Times New Roman, Alvar Aalto, propaganda, Le Corbusier, Playboy, Porsche, Windows, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Putin 3x</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20190420-poetin-3x/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20190420-poetin-3x/</guid>
      <description>Three portraits Putin viewed from different angles: three portraits from 2017-2018. Two are long (American and British), one is very long (Russian, with subtitles). Links to shorter clips are at the bottom.
The Power of Putin – BBC Documentary (Astrobum, 2017, 43 m)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
