<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>русский с носителем on Rusland 1</title>
    <link>/en/trefwoorden/%D1%80%D1%83%D1%81%D1%81%D0%BA%D0%B8%D0%B9-%D1%81-%D0%BD%D0%BE%D1%81%D0%B8%D1%82%D0%B5%D0%BB%D0%B5%D0%BC/</link>
    <description>Recent content in русский с носителем on Rusland 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/trefwoorden/%D1%80%D1%83%D1%81%D1%81%D0%BA%D0%B8%D0%B9-%D1%81-%D0%BD%D0%BE%D1%81%D0%B8%D1%82%D0%B5%D0%BB%D0%B5%D0%BC/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VERBS</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20240822-werkwoordenschat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20240822-werkwoordenschat/</guid>
      <description>Here is a selection of resources and channels you can use to do just that. Limited to the basic verbs, leaving out the special and more complex ones (verbs of motion, verbs on -ся, verbs with prepositions) for the most part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fifth Case: Instrumental</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20210113-vijfde-naamval-instrumentalis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20210113-vijfde-naamval-instrumentalis/</guid>
      <description>Usage Professions We say: he works as a lawyer, or: he is a lawyer. Russian can do that without &amp;ldquo;as&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;is.&amp;rdquo; Кем он работает = what does he work as, what is his profession. Кто (who) in the instrumental case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian Antonyms (антонимы)</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20201223-russische-antoniemen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20201223-russische-antoniemen/</guid>
      <description>Negation Often, if you don’t know the antonym of an adjective, it&amp;rsquo;s not a big problem. Just add не (not) in front of it, and you&amp;rsquo;re done. This is similar to the English prefixes &amp;ldquo;un-&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;in-&amp;rdquo;: unattractive, unwise, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian Abbreviations, Truncations, and Acronyms</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20201210-russische-afkortingen-inkortingen-acroniemen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20201210-russische-afkortingen-inkortingen-acroniemen/</guid>
      <description>и т.д. etc. Starting with a common abbreviation (аббревиатура) that you often use at the end. и т.д. (note the space after и) = etc., as it stands for и так далее, meaning &amp;ldquo;and so on&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;and so forth&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fourth Case: Accusative</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20201125-vierde-naamval-accusatief/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20201125-vierde-naamval-accusatief/</guid>
      <description>Usage Direct Object The fourth case, or accusative, is used when something happens to someone or something. In the sentence, it acts as the direct object. For example: &amp;ldquo;I buy a magazine, I read the newspaper.&amp;rdquo; Magazine and newspaper are direct objects (and take the accusative case) because they are being bought or read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian Calendar Words: Months and Days</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20201118-russische-kalenderwoorden-maanden-en-dagen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20201118-russische-kalenderwoorden-maanden-en-dagen/</guid>
      <description>January–December Let’s start with the months of the year. They&amp;rsquo;re not particularly exciting—no more interesting than the names you&amp;rsquo;re used to. The origins are the same: Roman gods and goddesses (January, March, May, June), words (February, April), emperors (July, August), and numbers (September through December).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflexive and Intransitive: Verbs Ending in -ся</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20201108-wederkerend-en-onovergankelijk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20201108-wederkerend-en-onovergankelijk/</guid>
      <description>The sound of я in this context is more like &amp;ldquo;a&amp;rdquo; than &amp;ldquo;ya.&amp;rdquo; In conjugations, you&amp;rsquo;ll see both -ся and -сь endings.
Intransitive These verbs don&amp;rsquo;t take a direct object. Compare Я открываю дверь (I open the door) with Дверь открывается (the door opens).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian Superstitions</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20200824-russisch-bijgeloof/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20200824-russisch-bijgeloof/</guid>
      <description>Etiquette Besides being amusing and interesting, it&amp;rsquo;s useful to know some of these. A number of them have become social norms or etiquette. For example, don&amp;rsquo;t shake hands on the threshold. Don’t give an even number of flowers unless it&amp;rsquo;s for a funeral.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Be or Not to Be</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20200818-zijn-of-niet-zijn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20200818-zijn-of-niet-zijn/</guid>
      <description>Present Tense In the present tense, it&amp;rsquo;s simply not needed.
He is happy: он счастлив.That is strange: это странно.
Russian to be in the present tense – быть в настоящем времени (Russian with Natasha, 2016, 17 m) Russian Grammar: Verb to Be in Present Tense (Fun Russian, 2012, 2 m) Making sentences You will encounter the verb in famous lines like Shakespeare&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;To be or not to be&amp;rdquo;—быть или не быть.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Words ending in ь</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20200716-woorden-eindigend-op-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20200716-woorden-eindigend-op-b/</guid>
      <description>Masculine A word ending in ь is masculine in the following cases:
Natural gender Words that refer to a man are grammatically masculine. Think of царь (tsar), король (king), зять (son-in-law), and парень (boy, boyfriend, young man).
Calendar months All months in Russian are masculine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questions and Question Words</title>
      <link>/en/taal/200229-vraagwoorden/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/200229-vraagwoorden/</guid>
      <description>How, what, where, etc. If you want to ask when or how he&amp;rsquo;s going, what he&amp;rsquo;s studying, or which university he’s attending, of course, you’ll need question words. These are also not difficult.
Here are the most important ones:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Pronouns</title>
      <link>/en/taal/200224-persoonlijk-voornaamwoord/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/200224-persoonlijk-voornaamwoord/</guid>
      <description>The forms of the second and fourth cases (genitive and accusative) are even identical.
именительный родительный дательный винительный творительный предложный я меня мне меня мной (обо) мне ты тебя тебе тебя тобой (о) тебе он/оно его ему его им (о) нём она её ей её ей (о) ней мы нас нам нас нами (о) нас вы вас вам вас вами (о) вас они их им их ими (о) них Russian Personal Pronouns – Nominative Case (Learn Russian Now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Russian with Song Lyrics (1)</title>
      <link>/en/taal/190613-songteksten-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/190613-songteksten-1/</guid>
      <description>Звезда A great first option is Звезда (Star). With a page of explanation and translation (Explore Russian). The song (2013) is by Глюк’oZa or Glukoza (website, Wikipedia). From the same channel are Вечная молодость (Eternal Youth), also with explanation and translation, and an analysis of Синие сугробы (Blue Snowdrifts).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
