<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Be Fluent in Russian on Rusland 1</title>
    <link>/en/trefwoorden/be-fluent-in-russian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Be Fluent in Russian on Rusland 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/trefwoorden/be-fluent-in-russian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stress (Ударение)</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20210304-klemtoon-in-russisch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20210304-klemtoon-in-russisch/</guid>
      <description>Interests Catalógus or catálogus? The latter is correct (traceable to the Greek), but no one looks strangely if you say catalógus. In Russian, emphasis is more important. It can determine both the pronunciation of a word (an stressed syllable sometimes sounds very different from an unstressed one) and its spelling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imperative Mood (Imperative)</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20210128-gebiedende-wijs-imperatief/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20210128-gebiedende-wijs-imperatief/</guid>
      <description>You need to know a few things to be able to do this in Russian. Take a look.
они-form To form the imperative mood in Russian, you start with the они (they) conjugation of the verb. Remove the ending and replace it with something else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian Ordinal Numbers</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20201127-russische-rangtelwoorden/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20201127-russische-rangtelwoorden/</guid>
      <description>Third is an exception too, and it just keeps going.
Applications It’s worth mentioning, because otherwise you might think it’s unimportant or uninteresting. You definitely need ordinal numbers for dates. For instance, we say: today is the 27th. You can get a preview in Ordinal numbers and dates in Russian (Learn Russian with Alfia, 2020, 22 m).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The letter ы</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20200826-de-letter-bi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20200826-de-letter-bi/</guid>
      <description>Sounds Like An indescribable sound, indeed. But people have tried. Wikipedia loosely describes it as “like the u in bunker” (which is far off). Wikibooks says it’s somewhere between &amp;ldquo;u&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;j&amp;rdquo;, while Russisch in Rusland compares it to something between &amp;ldquo;u&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;i&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Grammar Unnecessary?</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20200724-grammatica-onnodig/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20200724-grammatica-onnodig/</guid>
      <description>Vocabulary first Being a vlogger, Bankrupt (or Rich) exaggerates a bit, of course. Still, he manages to get by in all Russian-speaking countries. And when there are language problems: ‘Every single time I’ve been misunderstood, has been because either I didn’t know the Russian word, or I didn’t understand the Russian word that they were using.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Learn Russian?</title>
      <link>/en/taal/190612-waarom-russisch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/190612-waarom-russisch/</guid>
      <description>Plus everything listed below.
Why Study Russian? (Amazing Russian, 2016, 8 m)
Why Learn Russian? – 5 Reasons (Real Russian Club, 2018, 4 m)
Why You Should Learn Russian Language (Be Fluent in Russian, 2018, 8 m)
From the same channel:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Sentences</title>
      <link>/en/taal/190525-zinnen-maken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/190525-zinnen-maken/</guid>
      <description>Word Order Cats eat mice can also be expressed in Russian as mice eat cats. There’s a lot of freedom in word order. The price for that freedom is declensions and cases. They keep sentences simple but constantly change the words.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gluing Sounds</title>
      <link>/en/taal/190421-klanken-plakken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/190421-klanken-plakken/</guid>
      <description>From Letters to Words The first step in Russian – learning the alphabet – is already a big step forward. Once you know the letters and their sounds, you can immediately read and pronounce a lot. You just glue the sounds together and try not to stumble.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
