<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Russian grammar on Rusland 1</title>
    <link>/en/trefwoorden/russian-grammar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Russian grammar on Rusland 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/trefwoorden/russian-grammar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SIXTH NOUN: LOCATIVE/PREPOSITIONAL</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20240601_zesde_naamval__locatief_prepositional/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20240601_zesde_naamval__locatief_prepositional/</guid>
      <description>Here (only) about usage; conjugations in a subsequent section, though you will inevitably encounter them below. Location The main use of the sixth noun is to designate a place - the name “locative” already indicates it, most other uses flow from it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perfective and imperfective</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20210406-perfectief_en_imperfectief/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20210406-perfectief_en_imperfectief/</guid>
      <description>Result or process Russian verbs are either perfective (совершенный вид, сов./св.) or imperfective (несовершенный вид, нес./нсв.) and thus form pairs. The first expresses result (a completed action), the second process, unfinished or repeated action. To compare with the difference between reading out and reading in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>O and A: Tolstoy, Bolshoi and krakadil Gena</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20210311-o_en_a_tolstoj_bolshoi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20210311-o_en_a_tolstoj_bolshoi/</guid>
      <description>Oh and ah The o is the most common letter in Russian (as mentioned in Paste Sounds). Were all those o&amp;rsquo;s to have an o sound, the whole language would have changed sound. Now it has been determined that an unstressed o (usually) sounds like an a, and that was a good idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imperative Mood (Imperative)</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20210128-gebiedende-wijs-imperatief/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20210128-gebiedende-wijs-imperatief/</guid>
      <description>You need to know a few things to be able to do this in Russian. Take a look.
они-form To form the imperative mood in Russian, you start with the они (they) conjugation of the verb. Remove the ending and replace it with something else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian Adjectives (Прилагательные)</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20201219-russische-bijvoeglijk-naamwoorden/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20201219-russische-bijvoeglijk-naamwoorden/</guid>
      <description>Declensions Flexible First, you need to know how to decline them. Russian adjectives are flexible: they adapt to the gender and number of the noun they modify. New text, new idea, new morning, new plans: новый текст (m.), новая идея (f.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian Ordinal Numbers</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20201127-russische-rangtelwoorden/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20201127-russische-rangtelwoorden/</guid>
      <description>Third is an exception too, and it just keeps going.
Applications It’s worth mentioning, because otherwise you might think it’s unimportant or uninteresting. You definitely need ordinal numbers for dates. For instance, we say: today is the 27th. You can get a preview in Ordinal numbers and dates in Russian (Learn Russian with Alfia, 2020, 22 m).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fourth Case: Accusative</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20201125-vierde-naamval-accusatief/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20201125-vierde-naamval-accusatief/</guid>
      <description>Usage Direct Object The fourth case, or accusative, is used when something happens to someone or something. In the sentence, it acts as the direct object. For example: &amp;ldquo;I buy a magazine, I read the newspaper.&amp;rdquo; Magazine and newspaper are direct objects (and take the accusative case) because they are being bought or read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Third Case: Dative</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20200818-derde-naamval-datief/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20200818-derde-naamval-datief/</guid>
      <description>Use дательный падеж when someone or something receives something. Here&amp;rsquo;s how and when to use it.
Usage You use дательный падеж in the following situations.
Indirect Object When something is given or directed at someone. Often, the recipient is a person, and the dative case takes over the role of &amp;ldquo;to&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Be or Not to Be</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20200818-zijn-of-niet-zijn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20200818-zijn-of-niet-zijn/</guid>
      <description>Present Tense In the present tense, it&amp;rsquo;s simply not needed.
He is happy: он счастлив.That is strange: это странно.
Russian to be in the present tense – быть в настоящем времени (Russian with Natasha, 2016, 17 m) Russian Grammar: Verb to Be in Present Tense (Fun Russian, 2012, 2 m) Making sentences You will encounter the verb in famous lines like Shakespeare&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;To be or not to be&amp;rdquo;—быть или не быть.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second Case: Genitive</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20200419-tweede-naamval-genitief/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20200419-tweede-naamval-genitief/</guid>
      <description>Usage Of the The genitive is a &amp;lsquo;of the&amp;rsquo; (or &amp;lsquo;of the&amp;rsquo;) case. Where Dutch uses compound words (schoonheidssalon, wereldkampioenschap) and English uses separate words (beauty salon, world championship), Russian uses the second case for such things. Thus, you get салон красоты (salon of beauty) and чемпионат мира (championship of the world).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Past Tense</title>
      <link>/en/taal/200217-verleden-tijd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/200217-verleden-tijd/</guid>
      <description>Three Forms (or Actually Four) Masculine, feminine, and formal or plural: verbs in the past tense take on only three forms. Or actually four, but the form for оно (it) is rarely used. After all, an оно doesn’t (or didn’t) do much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First and Second Conjugation</title>
      <link>/en/taal/200216-eerste-en-tweede-vervoeging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/200216-eerste-en-tweede-vervoeging/</guid>
      <description>It is useful – and inevitable – to learn these conjugations. The same patterns recur frequently.
Learn Russian Verbs The series Глаголы (verbs) from LearnRussian.org teaches you verbs in a manageable set of five at a time. Conjugations and applications in sentences, along with short stories and the voice of Anastacia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masculine, Feminine, Neuter</title>
      <link>/en/taal/190611-mannelijk-vrouwelijk-onzijdig/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/190611-mannelijk-vrouwelijk-onzijdig/</guid>
      <description>Exceptions For every rule, there’s an exception. имя (name) and время (time) are neuter, кофе (coffee) is masculine, and there are more examples like these. And if a word ends in ь (мягкий знак, the soft sign), it can be either masculine or feminine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Sentences</title>
      <link>/en/taal/190525-zinnen-maken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/190525-zinnen-maken/</guid>
      <description>Word Order Cats eat mice can also be expressed in Russian as mice eat cats. There’s a lot of freedom in word order. The price for that freedom is declensions and cases. They keep sentences simple but constantly change the words.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
