<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>knowledge on Rusland 1</title>
    <link>/en/taal_onderwerpen/knowledge/</link>
    <description>Recent content in knowledge on Rusland 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/taal_onderwerpen/knowledge/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>John Cleese – How about Russian?</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20210222-how-about-russian-john-cleese-doet-lermontov/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20210222-how-about-russian-john-cleese-doet-lermontov/</guid>
      <description>Lermontov The words he speaks are from Молитва (Prayer), a short poem (1839) by Mikhail Lermontov. He starts (at 0:29) with the second stanza (Есть сила благодатная, в созвучьи слов живых) and continues with the first one – which Wanda cannot know, and apparently, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter much either.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Beauty of the Russian Language</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20210107-schoonheid-van-het-russisch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20210107-schoonheid-van-het-russisch/</guid>
      <description>Lomonosov The quote is from Mikhail Lomonosov (= Михаил Ломоносов, 1711-1765). English translations vary slightly; see also (the one in) On This Day in 1711 Mikhail Lomonosov Was Born (The Moscow Times, 19-11-2019) and Lomonosov’s Dedication to His Russian Grammar (Cambridge, 2017, also available on Jstor).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wegmans? The Name Putin and the Word путь</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20201214-de-naam-poetin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20201214-de-naam-poetin/</guid>
      <description>Mr. Wegmans You can listen to it here. Around 2:54, you’ll hear that the name probably comes from путь (put), meaning &amp;lsquo;way&amp;rsquo; (or &amp;lsquo;path&amp;rsquo;). Ms. Rutten sticks to Wegmans and doesn’t say mister. She does mention it&amp;rsquo;s a cute name, but someone interrupts her at that point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Does Russian Sound Like?</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20201130-hoe-klinkt-russisch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20201130-hoe-klinkt-russisch/</guid>
      <description>Harsh A common and crude judgment about Russian is that it’s rude or грубо, meaning rough or harsh.
Why Russian Sounds Rude (Rush into Russian, 2020, 32 m) Почему Русские звучат так грубо (Джастин, 2020, 7 m), also see 2 Причины Русские Звучат Грубо На Английском (2019, 4 m) Backwards &amp;ldquo;Like someone’s playing a vinyl backwards,&amp;rdquo; according to Trevor Noah in Some Languages Are Scary (2018), imitation from 4:06.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russians and English</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20201122-russen-en-engels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20201122-russen-en-engels/</guid>
      <description>English is Difficult For native Russian speakers, English is just as foreign as Russian is for English speakers. It’s challenging for Russians to learn English, and the sounds feel unnatural. To them, English sounds like you have a hot potato in your throat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family Name, First Name, and Patronymic (FIO) and Names in Russian</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20200722-familie-voor-en-vadersnaam-en-namen-in-het-russisch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20200722-familie-voor-en-vadersnaam-en-namen-in-het-russisch/</guid>
      <description>Learn more in What is отчество in Russian?! Abbreviation ФИО in Russian (Ru-Land Club, 2017, 9 m) and Basic guide to Russian names | Name, Last Name &amp;amp; Patronymic in Russian (Daria Mikhay, 2017, 5 m).
Son or daughter The отчество (óhtjestva) is slightly different for a son than for a daughter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
