<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>history on Rusland 1</title>
    <link>/en/land_en_volk_onderwerpen/history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in history on Rusland 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/land_en_volk_onderwerpen/history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tucker Carlson and Vladimir Putin</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20240606_tucker_carlson_en_vladmir_poetin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20240606_tucker_carlson_en_vladmir_poetin/</guid>
      <description>Rurik About a quarter of the more than two-hour interview was devoted to answering the first question, or rather, to Putin’s opening monologue. It began in 862 with Prince Rurik; from there, returning to the present was quite the journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Samizdat (Down with Big Tech)</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20210316-samizdat_weg-met-big-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20210316-samizdat_weg-met-big-tech/</guid>
      <description>Self/DIY The word самиздат roughly translates to self- or DIY publishing. Сам (sam) means self, издатель means publisher. If you search for the term, you’ll often come across services offering self-publishing and self-funded book publishing. Вас могут читать уже сегодня!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flag and Emblem (2/2): Saint George and the Eagle</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20210308-wapen_van_rusland/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20210308-wapen_van_rusland/</guid>
      <description>Eagle East versus West or symbol of national schizophrenia, it’s not about that. The two-headed eagle (also seen in Albania, Serbia, and Montenegro) was used in the Byzantine Empire (and even earlier) and expresses unity rather than contradiction or division.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joeri Gagarin (1934-1968)</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20210130-joeri-gagarin-1934-1968/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20210130-joeri-gagarin-1934-1968/</guid>
      <description>The First There are doubts about whether Gagarin was really the first person in space. Some claim others went before him but didn&amp;rsquo;t survive. Gagarin, they say, didn&amp;rsquo;t deserve the honor because he didn&amp;rsquo;t land according to the rules (inside the Vostok 1 capsule).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mother of God on the Moat: St. Basil’s Cathedral</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20210109-basiliuskathedraal-saint-basils-cathedral/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20210109-basiliuskathedraal-saint-basils-cathedral/</guid>
      <description>Ivan IV Built to commemorate the Conquest of Kazan on the orders of Ivan IV (1530-1584), better known as the Terrible or Грозный. While the name translates to &amp;ldquo;terrible,&amp;rdquo; it&amp;rsquo;s a bit exaggerated – as a character sketch, it&amp;rsquo;s still mild.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian Matryoshka Yes</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20201212-russische-matroesjka/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20201212-russische-matroesjka/</guid>
      <description>Matryoshka ≠ Babushka I get it, you’ll say, but not everyone understands or knows that. The matryoshka is often called a babushka – and really, it’s better to say nothing at all if you’re going to say that.
Difficult for Mrs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yury Dud’s Kolyma</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20200712-yury-duds-kolyma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20200712-yury-duds-kolyma/</guid>
      <description>Reviews More at New Russian Documentary Brings the Horrors of the Gulag to the YouTube Generation (Alexey Kovalev, tol.org 2019) and articles on Johnson’s Russia List and vsem.ru. Review by Veniamin Zima (a historian) on realnoevremya.com, in English and/or Russian.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State Funeral</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/200215-state-funeral/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/200215-state-funeral/</guid>
      <description>Monty Pythonesque, reported de Volkskrant, but close to historical reality. Quite high praise for a film featuring supposed Russians speaking English.
State Funeral Much more interesting and far closer to historical reality is State Funeral (2019, in Russian Государственные Похороны), by Ukrainian director Sergei Loznitsa.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
