<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>symbol on Rusland 1</title>
    <link>/en/trefwoorden/symbol/</link>
    <description>Recent content in symbol on Rusland 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/trefwoorden/symbol/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Flag and Emblem (2/2): Saint George and the Eagle</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20210308-wapen_van_rusland/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20210308-wapen_van_rusland/</guid>
      <description>Eagle East versus West or symbol of national schizophrenia, it’s not about that. The two-headed eagle (also seen in Albania, Serbia, and Montenegro) was used in the Byzantine Empire (and even earlier) and expresses unity rather than contradiction or division.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flag and Emblem (1/2): Russian Flag</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20210228-russische-vlag/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20210228-russische-vlag/</guid>
      <description>Meaning There are several interpretations regarding the reasoning behind this tricolor. One says white stands for God, blue for the tsar or king, and red for the land and people. More commonly, the colors are linked to noble qualities: white for purity, blue for loyalty, red for courage, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Motherland Calls! Mother of all Statues</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20201120-moederland-roept-moeder-aller-standbeelden/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20201120-moederland-roept-moeder-aller-standbeelden/</guid>
      <description>Facts and Figures More facts and figures about The Motherland Calls (also known as Mother Russia) can be found on Wikipedia in English, Dutch, and Russian. Also see The Motherland Calls – Mother Russia (Historiek.net) and «Родина-мать зовет!» 10 Facts about the Monument (Culture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian National Anthem</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20200403-russisch-volkslied/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20200403-russisch-volkslied/</guid>
      <description>The text begins, in both of the first two sentences, simply with Россия (Russia). Our sacred might (священная наша держава), our beloved country (любимая наша страна). No foreign blood or king from afar. Putin The current National Anthem of the Russian Federation was (re)established in 2000 by Vladimir Putin.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
