<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pop on Rusland 1</title>
    <link>/en/genres/pop/</link>
    <description>Recent content in pop on Rusland 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/genres/pop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wolves in the Shooting Range (Волки в тире)</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20240604-wolven_in_de_schietbaan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20240604-wolven_in_de_schietbaan/</guid>
      <description>War Title track from the album (YouTube, Bandcamp, Spotify) released in 2023. Featuring девять песен о войне, nine songs about war, с ее похоронами в финале, with its funeral in the finale (Meduza 2023). Video clip by Какой-то либерал, 2023 Lyrics, lyrics with translation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manizha 3x</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20210326-manizha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20210326-manizha/</guid>
      <description>Strong There’s not much to the message if you just listen to the chorus. Every Russian woman should know she is strong, but that’s in English (lyrics). Still, it was enough to cause controversy: see for example Russia&amp;rsquo;s Eurovision entry to be investigated for &amp;lsquo;illegal&amp;rsquo; lyrics (The Guardian, 18-03-2021) and Conservative Russia in retreat as Tajik refugee raps her way to Eurovision (The Telegraph, 13-03-2021).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>25/17 3x</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20210313-2517/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20210313-2517/</guid>
      <description>25/17 is/was Ant (Ant) or Anton Zavyalov (1982) and Bledny (Pale) or Andrey Pozdnukhov (1976).
Подорожник (Plantain) (2014) From the album Русский подорожник (Russian plantain). Featuring Dmitry Revyakin (= Dmitry Revyakin), from Kalinov Most (= Kalinov Most). Performed again in 2020 on Evening Urgant; see the playlist Music Performances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DenDerty (Денис Бурашников) 3x</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20210215-denderty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20210215-denderty/</guid>
      <description>Тотальное Самоубийство (Total Suicide, 2015) A monologue fragment from the post-nuclear science fiction film Письма мёртвого человека (Dead Man’s Letters, 1986). See Wikipedia English or Russian, watch on Ivi.tv or Culture.ru (also on YouTube after logging in).
Сейчас я уйду в свою комнату и для меня всё кончится.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ЛЮТИК – 7 whisky-colas and Tired of Drinking</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20210127-lyutik-sasha-moskalets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20210127-lyutik-sasha-moskalets/</guid>
      <description>7 виски кол Whisky-cola, for example. It starts with two and quickly moves to five. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop there, nor at the seven mentioned in the title. I’m having so much fun (мне так весело) – I hope I forget everything (надеюсь всё забуду) as soon as I get home (как только я зайду в свой дом).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anacondaz 4x</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20201215-anacondaz-4x/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20201215-anacondaz-4x/</guid>
      <description>Всё хорошо (2019) From Мои дети не будут скучать (2019).
Всё хорошо. Повеситься или повесить ружьё? Да ну, что за мысли. Ведь всё хорошо! (всё хорошо!) Перезимовали за гаражом, радуюсь так, будто не заражён Ныряли ведь в пруд голышом – значит Бог защитит Значит всё хорошо</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Дайте танк 3x</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20201123-daite-tank-3x/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20201123-daite-tank-3x/</guid>
      <description>With the added bonus of strong lyrics. See Тексты Дайте танк (!) – лучшие в русской музыке (СЕИН, 2020, 24 m) and «Ещё одна новая волна»: читаем тексты группы Дайте Танк (!) (Yandex Zen, 2019).
From Kolomna (or Коломна), active since 2007.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monetochka (Elizaveta Gyrdymova)</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20201101-monetochka-elizaveta-gyrdymova/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20201101-monetochka-elizaveta-gyrdymova/</guid>
      <description>Balloon Her voice was also mentioned on Вечерний Ургант (December 2018), where host Ivan Urgant says у вас очень красивый голос, you have a very beautiful voice. Monetochka then inhales helium from a balloon to lower the pitch. Even she is surprised by the result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ras Orchestra – No Way Back (Нет пути назад)</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20201031-ras-orchestra-njet-puti-nazad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20201031-ras-orchestra-njet-puti-nazad/</guid>
      <description>So what. If the weather gods aren’t cooperating, the true rasta man or woman will make it sunny themselves. Jah (in Russian Джа) is great.
Njet puti nazad The opening track is by Ras Orchestra (not to be confused with Rasta Orchestra).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dora &amp; Tanny Volkova – Doradoera</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20200712-dora-tanny-volkova-dora-doera/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20200712-dora-tanny-volkova-dora-doera/</guid>
      <description>Superdoera In Дорадура (Doradoera), Dora talks about herself. Because Dora goes through things, and things go wrong. With dates and such. Flights of fancy from the heart. All because (всё потому, что) Dora is a fool (Дора – дура): Dora is a fool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Дельфин 3x</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20200624-dolphin-3x/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20200624-dolphin-3x/</guid>
      <description>Весна (2008) Text
Дельфин on the clip below and (his memories of) the 1980 Olympics on Together with Дельфин, we remember the clip &amp;ldquo;Весна&amp;rdquo; (Sports.ru, 2020).
Надя (2014) Text
520 (2018) Text
Bonus: Без Нас (Without Us, 2008); more music on Spotify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TапОК – Every Day is Winter</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20200620-tapok-alle-dagen-winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20200620-tapok-alle-dagen-winter/</guid>
      <description>And then, the холодильник (fridge) and the кошелёк (wallet) are also пустой (empty).
From Гроза Танцполов, released in 2017. Text
More about TапОК or TapOK on Facebook and VK.
Recent (2020) is the album Кончало. Listen via Apple Music, Spotify, or YouTube (Playlist).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Murakami 3x</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20200227-murakami-3x/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20200227-murakami-3x/</guid>
      <description>Here are three songs from the period 2013-2018.
Бред (2013) Вдох на прощание Пообещай мне всё изменить Так бесполезно Это не честно, падая в бездну Любить
Text
Невозможно (2015) И бесполезно тащить вниз, иди с собою на компромисс; И ждать последний удар в висок – невозможно так!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grechka – Picture</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20200214-grechka-plaatje/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20200214-grechka-plaatje/</guid>
      <description>Prikrasnaja kartina A картина can be anything – an image, a photo, or a painting. &amp;ldquo;Picture&amp;rdquo; should cover it all, but Grechka still can’t reach it.
In the opening verse, it&amp;rsquo;s already mentioned that между нами дождь, и расстояние: between us, there is rain and distance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Komsomolsk 3x</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/190525-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BC%D1%81%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%BE%D0%BB%D1%8C%D1%81%D0%BA-3x/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/190525-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BC%D1%81%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%BE%D0%BB%D1%8C%D1%81%D0%BA-3x/</guid>
      <description>Азбука плохого вкуса (ABC of bad taste, 2017) The lyrics appear on screen.
Азбука Вкуса (ABC of Taste) is a supermarket.
Всё исчезло (Everything disappeared, 2018) I clicked somewhere (я нажала что-то) and everything disappeared (исчезло всё). Everyone has their own swamp (у каждого своё болото); watch how everything will disappear (смотри как всё исчезнет).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animal ДжаZ – Three Stripes</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/190425-animal-%D0%B4%D0%B6%D0%B0z-drie-strepen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/190425-animal-%D0%B4%D0%B6%D0%B0z-drie-strepen/</guid>
      <description>Jeans and Sneakers Джинсы порезаны: jeans cut. Лето: summer. Три полоски на кедах: three stripes on sneakers. Под теплым дождем: in the warm rain. There is also a lyrics version, a performance with Amatory, and one with Alai Oli.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Би-2 – Hipster</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/190421-%D0%B1%D0%B8-2hipster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/190421-%D0%B1%D0%B8-2hipster/</guid>
      <description>London vibes Узкие джинсы, майка с принтом = skinny jeans and a shirt with a print. This rhymes with В целом не важно что будет потом: generally, it doesn’t matter what comes after. Лечь на дно (lit.: lie on the bottom) with your London music (вместе с музыкой Лондона), all gone by (всё прошло) and out of style (всё такое не модное).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
