<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>acoustic on Rusland 1</title>
    <link>/en/genres/acoustic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in acoustic on Rusland 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/genres/acoustic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Zoloto (Vladimir Zolotukhin) 3x</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20210302-zoloto-vladimir-zolotukhin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20210302-zoloto-vladimir-zolotukhin/</guid>
      <description>Compare the studio versions of Останемся здесь (We’ll stay here) and Улицы ждали (The streets were waiting) with the two below. A ukulele, the wind, and an acoustic guitar: might sound like little, but it was just enough. Both are from 8 Месяцев в Вегасе (8 Months in Vegas, 2019), also featured in a documentary film (Kana Beisekeyev, 2020, 25 min).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ручеёк – I often had this dream &amp; Elenberg</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20201220-rucheyok-ik-had-vaak-deze-droom-elenberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20201220-rucheyok-ik-had-vaak-deze-droom-elenberg/</guid>
      <description>A ручеёк is a stream or brook. It&amp;rsquo;s also a game (for ages 7 and up), somewhat similar to a folk dance. As you might guess, Ручеёк doesn’t play rock and roll.
Мне часто снилса этот сон (I often had this dream) and Elenberg are from Первое собрание (First Collection, 2016).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timur Mutsurayev (Тимур Муцураев) 3x</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20201128-timur-mutsurayev-3x/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20201128-timur-mutsurayev-3x/</guid>
      <description>Mutsurayev, whether he wants it or not, is forever a friend of the Russian language. And of Russian-language songs. Here are three, and let’s be honest.
Candles Extinguished Tekst
On YouTube, there’s also a static clip. Living room versions by, among others, Васяга (2018) and Тимур И Жанна (2012).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yanka Dyagileva </title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20200812-yanka-dyagileva/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20200812-yanka-dyagileva/</guid>
      <description>She was never able to record anything with professional sound quality, but somehow, her music doesn’t seem to suffer for it—in fact, it almost seems like it was made for this rawness. It was difficult to choose just three tracks, so there are seven.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volodya Kotlyarov &amp; PornoFilms – It Will Pass (Это пройдёт)</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20200722-volodya-kotlyarov-pornofilmy-gaat-voorbij/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20200722-volodya-kotlyarov-pornofilmy-gaat-voorbij/</guid>
      <description>I/We Ivan Golunov For more background and to provide Volodya with more context: Golunov was supported with (and on) the joint front page of three newspapers. Я/Мы Иван Голунов, by Vedomosti, Kommersant, and RBK.
See Russian journalist freed after fierce protests (Trouw, 10-06-2019) and Russian newspapers jointly support arrested colleague (Villamedia, 11-06-2019).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Konstantin Stupin – When I Died</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/190613-konstantin-stupin-toen-ik-stierf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/190613-konstantin-stupin-toen-ik-stierf/</guid>
      <description>Когда я умер взорвалось солнце: when I died, the sun exploded. And сметая звезды: swept away the stars.
Online sources that reveal the lyrics contradict each other on details. See &amp;amp; compare, for example, Tekstovoi.ru and – with chords as a bonus – MyChords.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
