<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title> lyrics on Rusland 1</title>
    <link>/en/trefwoorden/lyrics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in  lyrics on Rusland 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/trefwoorden/lyrics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Offret 3x</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20240519-offret-3x/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20240519-offret-3x/</guid>
      <description>Dark ‘Songs about the dark side of human nature,’ was once the description on Offret&amp;rsquo;s VK page – still visible in the headline of this interview (Idioteq, 2017). Nowadays, it has changed to: ‘black metal with dark synths and acoustic soundscapes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>До свиданья, дорогая!</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20210407-da_svidanija_daragaja/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20210407-da_svidanija_daragaja/</guid>
      <description>Я СМЕЛЕЙ (2019) I am braver – from their first and only album Себя потерял (2019).
A world of colorful paints But I am just a shadow Don’t look for me I’m braver Don’t look for me I’m braver Don’t look for me I’m braver The crescent moon Will fall on you from the sky Shattering hearts Into a thousand pieces It will stop And make you understand You will never love again You will never love again You will never love again</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gospod – Holy Metal and the Seven Deadly Sins</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20210305-gospod_holy_metal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20210305-gospod_holy_metal/</guid>
      <description>Greed The Main Sins of Humanity (2021) contains seven tracks, which shouldn’t come as a surprise. Greed is the first, and it makes you want more.
The lyrics were not found online, but here they are, with спасибо (thanks) to Gospod.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>телеэкран (Teleekran) 4x</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20201230-teleekran-4x/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20201230-teleekran-4x/</guid>
      <description>Капитан Радар (2020) From the Реактор EP (2020). Also featuring Плохо скрытый ужас and На радарах, which also has a live version. Lyrics available on the Bandcamp track page and here.
In cryogenic sleep, birthdays pass by And films lose their meaning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WLVS – Mirages (Миражи) and the two before it</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20201229-wlvs-mirages/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20201229-wlvs-mirages/</guid>
      <description>Just in time for 2020 came Миражи, which makes for a good moment to look at a trilogy of their work. Unlike what’s usually done here, we’ll go from old to new.
Lost Kids From March 2019. With a cool video and a pro-life message (сейчас мы выбираем жить – now we choose to live), even for those who might feel lost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convince – Religion</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20200627-convince-religie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20200627-convince-religie/</guid>
      <description>Terror Strong words about (and mostly against) religion. It is террор (terror), and зло (evil). Also the кнут (knout, whip) that drives you into the pen (что отправит в загон). You will pray (ты будешь молиться) but will not be saved (не будешь спасён).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
