<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>watch tip on Rusland 1</title>
    <link>/en/trefwoorden/watch-tip/</link>
    <description>Recent content in watch tip on Rusland 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/trefwoorden/watch-tip/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>There to find: In Russia (в России)</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20201225-in-rusland-in-russia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20201225-in-rusland-in-russia/</guid>
      <description>An exploration Well, Vincent Urban, Max Neumeier and Tim Höddinghaus are not just occasional filmmakers with a simple drone and camera. In Russia – в России is also (as described on YouTube, see there for more) ‘an exploration of all the different lenses, viewpoints, and expectations one can apply in a travel film’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian Tattoo Tour</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/200215-russian-tattoo-tour/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/200215-russian-tattoo-tour/</guid>
      <description>2071, 21 min, English subtitled. More on (and also available via) The Russian Tattoo Tour (In Russia).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State Funeral</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/200215-state-funeral/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/200215-state-funeral/</guid>
      <description>Monty Pythonesque, reported de Volkskrant, but close to historical reality. Quite high praise for a film featuring supposed Russians speaking English.
State Funeral Much more interesting and far closer to historical reality is State Funeral (2019, in Russian Государственные Похороны), by Ukrainian director Sergei Loznitsa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian Design</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20190422-russen-en-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20190422-russen-en-design/</guid>
      <description>Documentary by Sergey Shanovich (Сергей Шанович), Shandesign. Russian spoken, English subtitled, 53 min, from 2016. Short introduction here.
100 Years of Design Twenty designers and design collectives (RU) discuss the (international) design that has influenced them. Yury Gordon, Denis Bashev, Maxi Shilov, Stas Aki, Oleg Pashenko, Anton Schnaider (and others) on Bauhaus, Times New Roman, Alvar Aalto, propaganda, Le Corbusier, Playboy, Porsche, Windows, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
