<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>punk on Rusland 1</title>
    <link>/en/genres/punk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in punk on Rusland 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/genres/punk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Punk against Putin: Criminal State – Путин</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/criminal-state-putin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/criminal-state-putin/</guid>
      <description>Almost all Russians love their country, but not all love their leader(s). Especially not that one. Criminal State (est. 2010) makes it clear. Lyrics below, with translation here. Explicit lyrics.
Путин (2014) We want to live freely so that no one hinders us so that all scum dies the f*** out the cop and politician suck it punks don&amp;rsquo;t love Putin they reject all the bulls*** governments can f*** off all politicians to prison</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Йорш (Yorsh) 3x</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20210320-yorsh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20210320-yorsh/</guid>
      <description>Панк-рок – это мы (Punk Rock – That&amp;rsquo;s Us) (2018) From #Нетпутиназад (#NoWayBack, 2019). Just like Андерграунд (Underground), which also has a piano version (2020).
This is punk rock poetry. Nothing more, nothing less.
Punk rock, that&amp;rsquo;s me (Панк-рок - это я) Punk rock, that&amp;rsquo;s you (Панк-рок - это ты) Punk rock, that&amp;rsquo;s us (Панк-рок - это мы).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Стрела – Burn Beautifully (Гореть красиво)</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20210129-strela-brand-mooi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20210129-strela-brand-mooi/</guid>
      <description>Burn The world is on fire (Мир в огне) and what can you do about it. Or with whom.
Тут никого нет, there is no one here, Мы смотрим на мир, we are watching the world Каждый для каждого, each for themselves На то, как красиво горит, at how beautifully it burns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ПОРТ(812) 3x &#43; Маррадёры</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20201222-port812-3x/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20201222-port812-3x/</guid>
      <description>812 is the area code for Saint Petersburg, where ПОРТ(812) is based. The founding date, 8-12, is a nice coincidence.
Честь, свобода и любовь (2020) Honor, freedom, and love. And нет других богов—no other gods. From the album Подарок (Gift, 2020).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Индульгенция – Feministka</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20201121-indulgencia-feministka/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20201121-indulgencia-feministka/</guid>
      <description>Explained in Панк-католицизм группы «Индульгенция», the punk Catholicism of the band Indulgencia (Nihilist.li, 2017).
Oegarelaja The language used to address the feminist in the song isn’t exactly Christian. To start, she’s called угорелая (oegarelaja), which loosely translates to &amp;ldquo;crazy.&amp;rdquo; She’s also такая тупая (so dumb), like the whole world (как весь этот мир), and такая кривая (so crooked, skewed, wrong), like everyone around her (как все вокруг).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brigadniy Podryad – 20 brave boys</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20200809-brigadniy-podryad-20-dappere-jongens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20200809-brigadniy-podryad-20-dappere-jongens/</guid>
      <description>Group character sketch: У одного из них жена у других лишь вина / Что не допили до конца свой стакан винца – one of them has a wife, the others only regret that they couldn&amp;rsquo;t finish their glass of wine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volodya Kotlyarov &amp; PornoFilms – It Will Pass (Это пройдёт)</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20200722-volodya-kotlyarov-pornofilmy-gaat-voorbij/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20200722-volodya-kotlyarov-pornofilmy-gaat-voorbij/</guid>
      <description>I/We Ivan Golunov For more background and to provide Volodya with more context: Golunov was supported with (and on) the joint front page of three newspapers. Я/Мы Иван Голунов, by Vedomosti, Kommersant, and RBK.
See Russian journalist freed after fierce protests (Trouw, 10-06-2019) and Russian newspapers jointly support arrested colleague (Villamedia, 11-06-2019).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Тараканы! 3x</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20200720-tarakany-3x/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20200720-tarakany-3x/</guid>
      <description>Engagement Lyrically and thematically, Тараканы! is your classic punk(rock) band. Watch and listen to Дезертир из армии зла (Deserter from the army of evil, 2019), Ни рыбы, ни мяса (Neither fish nor fowl, 2018), Я не верю (I don&amp;rsquo;t believe), Что я могу изменить?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truckdrivers – Sparks Fly</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20200401-truckdrivers-vonken-vliegen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20200401-truckdrivers-vonken-vliegen/</guid>
      <description>It also rhymes with жизнью пахнет земля (the earth smells of life) and так наступает весна (so spring begins).
Punk rock from the Urals – with fire in the music, and in the video, besides fire, there’s also snow.
Text and chords</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pornofilmy (Порнофильмы) 3x</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20200212-pornofilmy-3x/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20200212-pornofilmy-3x/</guid>
      <description>Shopping Malls Название действительно странное (The name is indeed strange), singer Vladimir (or Volodya) Kotlyarov (Владимир Котляров) is told in an interview with Новая Газета (2017). Kotlyarov explains the band&amp;rsquo;s name as a metaphor for the reality of his environment—where the roads are terrible, the wages are as low as a beggar&amp;rsquo;s, and people aimlessly hang out in shopping malls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smeh 3x</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/190525-smex-3x/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/190525-smex-3x/</guid>
      <description>With some words of wisdom in the finale, to the tune of Let it Be: не еби (don’t mess with).
Мозг мне не еби (2016) Lyrics
Их радио (2018) This is their radio, this is their march (Это их радио, это их шествие).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13 мгновений весны – Without Faith</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/190427-13-%D0%BC%D0%B3%D0%BD%D0%BE%D0%B2%D0%B5%D0%BD%D0%B8%D0%B8%CC%86-%D0%B2%D0%B5%D1%81%D0%BD%D1%8B-zonder-geloof/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/190427-13-%D0%BC%D0%B3%D0%BD%D0%BE%D0%B2%D0%B5%D0%BD%D0%B8%D0%B8%CC%86-%D0%B2%D0%B5%D1%81%D0%BD%D1%8B-zonder-geloof/</guid>
      <description>Vera Без (bez) means without, вера (vera) means faith. It becomes веры (genitive case) due to the без. This song says: without faith in yourself (без веры в себя) you lose yourself (ты себя потеряешь). Just move forward (иди только вперёд) and then you&amp;rsquo;ll find out (и тогда ты узнаешь).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
