<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>corona on Rusland 1</title>
    <link>/en/trefwoorden/corona/</link>
    <description>Recent content in corona on Rusland 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/trefwoorden/corona/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Хадн дадн – 900 rubles &amp; home today (Мы сегодня дома)</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20201203-xadn-dadn-900-roebel-thuis-vandaag/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20201203-xadn-dadn-900-roebel-thuis-vandaag/</guid>
      <description>So, there’s nothing revolutionary in the title and no drama. The musical arrangement, performance, lyrical scope, and variation: on all these fronts, it’s more restrained than exuberant. It’s almost fragile. But then/then again.
И дорога луной озарилась вся Мы с тобой никогда не поссоримся И ладонь на слои распадается И асфальт под ногой уменьшается</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Russian during the pandemic</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20200708-russisch-leren-in-coronatijd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20200708-russisch-leren-in-coronatijd/</guid>
      <description>Resources and opportunities YouTube teachers (m/f) also stayed at home and made the best of it by continuing to create. Vlogs, lessons, webinars, and video compilations from home students: there was no shortage of material or opportunities. Also useful and entertaining outside of pandemic times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian Corona Song</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20200519-russisch-coronalied/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20200519-russisch-coronalied/</guid>
      <description>Virusnaya In Russia, they took a different approach. At least, that’s what Semjon Slepakov (Семен Слепаков) and Dzhavid Kurbanov (Джавид Курбанов) did, with Вирусная. Clip below – watch and listen. Be sure to check out Russian lesson with a Corona song on Russia in Words and Pictures, about Semjon and the k**-virus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Russian with Vladimir Putin (1/2)</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20200420-leer-russisch-met-poetin-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20200420-leer-russisch-met-poetin-1/</guid>
      <description>From jokes to weapons Several options are available, both in terms of channels and topics. As part of the Russian Listening Test (Playlist), Anastasia Semina (Russian with Anastasia) created Putin talks about his hobbies. Путин говорит о своих хобби (2017, 2 m) and Vladimir Putin makes jokes at the press conference (2016, 3 m).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grechka – Picture</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20200214-grechka-plaatje/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20200214-grechka-plaatje/</guid>
      <description>Prikrasnaja kartina A картина can be anything – an image, a photo, or a painting. &amp;ldquo;Picture&amp;rdquo; should cover it all, but Grechka still can’t reach it.
In the opening verse, it&amp;rsquo;s already mentioned that между нами дождь, и расстояние: between us, there is rain and distance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
