<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Russian with Tamara on Rusland 1</title>
    <link>/en/trefwoorden/russian-with-tamara/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Russian with Tamara on Rusland 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/trefwoorden/russian-with-tamara/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Russians on the Netherlands and the Dutch</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/russen_over_nederland_en_de_nederlanders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/russen_over_nederland_en_de_nederlanders/</guid>
      <description>Dasha and Tamara Dutch people are known for being direct, a sentiment often echoed by Tamara Zhirova, who would know, as she lives in Amsterdam. (Where she also teaches Russian. You can find her on YouTube.) An entertaining conversation, mainly thanks to Tamara, who also sings for us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>O and A: Tolstoy, Bolshoi and krakadil Gena</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20210311-o_en_a_tolstoj_bolshoi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20210311-o_en_a_tolstoj_bolshoi/</guid>
      <description>Oh and ah The o is the most common letter in Russian (as mentioned in Paste Sounds). Were all those o&amp;rsquo;s to have an o sound, the whole language would have changed sound. Now it has been determined that an unstressed o (usually) sounds like an a, and that was a good idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian Ordinal Numbers</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20201127-russische-rangtelwoorden/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20201127-russische-rangtelwoorden/</guid>
      <description>Third is an exception too, and it just keeps going.
Applications It’s worth mentioning, because otherwise you might think it’s unimportant or uninteresting. You definitely need ordinal numbers for dates. For instance, we say: today is the 27th. You can get a preview in Ordinal numbers and dates in Russian (Learn Russian with Alfia, 2020, 22 m).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Words ending in ь</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20200716-woorden-eindigend-op-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20200716-woorden-eindigend-op-b/</guid>
      <description>Masculine A word ending in ь is masculine in the following cases:
Natural gender Words that refer to a man are grammatically masculine. Think of царь (tsar), король (king), зять (son-in-law), and парень (boy, boyfriend, young man).
Calendar months All months in Russian are masculine.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
