<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A1 on Rusland 1</title>
    <link>/en/trefwoorden/a1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in A1 on Rusland 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/trefwoorden/a1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Russian Ordinal Numbers</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20201127-russische-rangtelwoorden/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20201127-russische-rangtelwoorden/</guid>
      <description>Third is an exception too, and it just keeps going.
Applications It’s worth mentioning, because otherwise you might think it’s unimportant or uninteresting. You definitely need ordinal numbers for dates. For instance, we say: today is the 27th. You can get a preview in Ordinal numbers and dates in Russian (Learn Russian with Alfia, 2020, 22 m).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nominative Case: именительный падеж</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20200417-eerste-naamval-nominatief/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20200417-eerste-naamval-nominatief/</guid>
      <description>What or who The nominative case is the unmodified or default form of a word. If nothing is being done to it in the sentence, you don’t need to do anything either.*)
This is my car, the book is thick: машина and книга stay as they are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questions and Question Words</title>
      <link>/en/taal/200229-vraagwoorden/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/200229-vraagwoorden/</guid>
      <description>How, what, where, etc. If you want to ask when or how he&amp;rsquo;s going, what he&amp;rsquo;s studying, or which university he’s attending, of course, you’ll need question words. These are also not difficult.
Here are the most important ones:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Pronouns</title>
      <link>/en/taal/200224-persoonlijk-voornaamwoord/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/200224-persoonlijk-voornaamwoord/</guid>
      <description>The forms of the second and fourth cases (genitive and accusative) are even identical.
именительный родительный дательный винительный творительный предложный я меня мне меня мной (обо) мне ты тебя тебе тебя тобой (о) тебе он/оно его ему его им (о) нём она её ей её ей (о) ней мы нас нам нас нами (о) нас вы вас вам вас вами (о) вас они их им их ими (о) них Russian Personal Pronouns – Nominative Case (Learn Russian Now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The letter Ё</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20200219-de-letter-e/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20200219-de-letter-e/</guid>
      <description>Yo The sound isn’t hard. It’s like the Yo in York, says the (English) Wikipedia. The Dutch version compares it to the jo in jokken (to fib). Russian sources often give examples like ёжик (jozhik, hedgehog) or ёлка (yolka, Christmas tree).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To have, to have, to have</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20200219-hebben/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20200219-hebben/</guid>
      <description>у &amp;hellip; есть Literally, a Russian doesn’t say &amp;ldquo;I have,&amp;rdquo; but rather &amp;ldquo;by me is.&amp;rdquo; For that &amp;ldquo;by,&amp;rdquo; you use у, &amp;ldquo;is&amp;rdquo; becomes есть, and in between comes the personal pronoun in the genitive (second case). This turns я (I) into меня.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First and Second Conjugation</title>
      <link>/en/taal/200216-eerste-en-tweede-vervoeging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/200216-eerste-en-tweede-vervoeging/</guid>
      <description>It is useful – and inevitable – to learn these conjugations. The same patterns recur frequently.
Learn Russian Verbs The series Глаголы (verbs) from LearnRussian.org teaches you verbs in a manageable set of five at a time. Conjugations and applications in sentences, along with short stories and the voice of Anastacia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Counting and Numbers</title>
      <link>/en/taal/200215-tellen-en-getallen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/200215-tellen-en-getallen/</guid>
      <description>The words for 1 and 2 can take different forms (respectively один, одна, одно and два or две). And when Russians count, instead of starting with один, they often begin with раз (time/once).
From 10 to 20 Once you can count from 1 to 10, you can easily go further.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masculine, Feminine, Neuter</title>
      <link>/en/taal/190611-mannelijk-vrouwelijk-onzijdig/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/190611-mannelijk-vrouwelijk-onzijdig/</guid>
      <description>Exceptions For every rule, there’s an exception. имя (name) and время (time) are neuter, кофе (coffee) is masculine, and there are more examples like these. And if a word ends in ь (мягкий знак, the soft sign), it can be either masculine or feminine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentences for Beginners</title>
      <link>/en/taal/190526-zinnen-voor-beginners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/190526-zinnen-voor-beginners/</guid>
      <description>Top 10 Words for Connecting Thoughts in Russian (RussianPod101, 2017, 4 m)
From the same channel:
150 Most Common Phrases in Russian (2019, 25 m) 100 Phrases Every Russian Beginner Must-Know (2018, 36 m) Top 25 Must-Know Russian Phrases (2015, 8 m) Learn the Top 10 Must-Know Russian Lines You Need for Introducing Yourself (2015, 5 m) Top Must-Know Expressions for Agreeing and Disagreeing (2017, 5 m) Simple Phrases</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Sentences</title>
      <link>/en/taal/190525-zinnen-maken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/190525-zinnen-maken/</guid>
      <description>Word Order Cats eat mice can also be expressed in Russian as mice eat cats. There’s a lot of freedom in word order. The price for that freedom is declensions and cases. They keep sentences simple but constantly change the words.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Piece of Cake: Russian Alphabet</title>
      <link>/en/taal/190412-abctje/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/190412-abctje/</guid>
      <description>Apps Starting simple is recommended. For Android users: Russian alphabet for kids is great for beginners and looks cheerful. You’ll also learn some basic words right away. Russian Alphabet is less about cheerfulness but is clear and practical. Some example words are (too) difficult for beginners.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
