<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rock on Rusland 1</title>
    <link>/en/genres/rock/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rock on Rusland 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/genres/rock/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Shokalsky Revenge</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20210217-shokalsky_revenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20210217-shokalsky_revenge/</guid>
      <description>The band (or duo) is no longer active, but this is not a bad legacy. The first three tracks can be found on Репортаж с места событий (2016).
28 Also appeared on the compilation Ты Quoi (Чудесаунд) (2019): Spotify, YouTube.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skverna – Butovo &amp; Привет красавица</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20210115-skverna-butovo-privet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20210115-skverna-butovo-privet/</guid>
      <description>There isn’t much more to say about Skverna (also Скверна, but not to be confused with this). The number of views on their YouTube channel would be higher if only their mothers checked it out once a month. Too bad for those moms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Кукрыниксы – No Big Deal (Это не беда)</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20210108-kukryniksy-niet-erg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20210108-kukryniksy-niet-erg/</guid>
      <description>Горшенев From Кукрыниксы (Kukryniksy), a Saint Petersburg band now defunct, with Это не беда (1999) as their most well-known legacy (along with Чёрная невеста, Знай, and Колдовство). The new band of lead singer Алексей Горшенёв (1975, brother of Михаил) is called Горшенев.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Louna 3x</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20201201-louna-3x/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20201201-louna-3x/</guid>
      <description>Beginning of a new circle Louna has a new album (October 2020), Начало нового круга (Beginning of a New Circle). It includes Станем стеной, Кто мы? (with Anacondaz), Из этих стен (recorded during the pandemic), and this Сигнал в пустоте (Signal in the Void).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Казускома 4x</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20200825-kazuscoma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20200825-kazuscoma/</guid>
      <description>The selection was heavily influenced by what could be embedded. As a result, the regrettable omission here includes Я не могу (I Can&amp;rsquo;t, 2019), Твой рот (Your Mouth, 2018), and Электрический Волк (Electric Wolf, 2018).
These ones could be included and they are not bad either.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>НАИВ – Heroes of Our Time</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20200713-naiv-helden-van-onze-tijd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20200713-naiv-helden-van-onze-tijd/</guid>
      <description>Antihero(es) Just as the protagonist Pechorin is no hero at all, НАИВ also features characters far from any heroic roles. They can be seen in the video, and two are mentioned by name in the lyrics. The смелый вождь (brave leader) can only be Putin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Korsika – Rage</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20200630-korsika-woede/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20200630-korsika-woede/</guid>
      <description>Text
Korsika (or KORSИKA) is from Moscow, has been active since 2007, and keeps going strong. Learn more about Korsika (or Kорсика) on Wikipedia (RU) and their official website.
More words for rage in Russian vocabulary about ANGER | Злые слова (Ru-Land Club, 2020, 12 m).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vadim Kurilev – Harakiri</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20200317-vadim-kurilev-harakiri/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20200317-vadim-kurilev-harakiri/</guid>
      <description>First line: Я привык превращать свою музыку в шум. I am used to turning my music into noise. Second line: Прятать страшные сны под обломки хардрока. Hiding scary dreams under the wreckage of hard rock. But Где-то я уже всё это видел.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Слот – Russian Soul</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/190525-%D1%81%D0%BB%D0%BE%D1%82-russische-ziel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/190525-%D1%81%D0%BB%D0%BE%D1%82-russische-ziel/</guid>
      <description>Defend In addition to this неофициальный клип (unofficial clip), there is also a cartoon version, a live version (2016), and as the icing on the cake (literally), a Ролик о России (clip about Russia) – with planes and tanks, bears and a tiger, soldiers, and much more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amatory – First</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/190412-amatory-eerste/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/190412-amatory-eerste/</guid>
      <description>In Your Blood And found in the lyrics. Of course, it’s a woman. Like яд (poison) and a вирус (virus). The singer is struggling with everything and gets impatient, время не ждёт, time doesn’t wait. &amp;ldquo;I’m going crazy,&amp;rdquo; he says with the words я схожу с ума.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
