<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Various on Rusland 1</title>
    <link>/en/land_en_volk_onderwerpen/various/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Various on Rusland 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/land_en_volk_onderwerpen/various/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Russians on the Netherlands and the Dutch</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/russen_over_nederland_en_de_nederlanders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/russen_over_nederland_en_de_nederlanders/</guid>
      <description>Dasha and Tamara Dutch people are known for being direct, a sentiment often echoed by Tamara Zhirova, who would know, as she lives in Amsterdam. (Where she also teaches Russian. You can find her on YouTube.) An entertaining conversation, mainly thanks to Tamara, who also sings for us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telegram (Better Than WhatsApp) and P. Durov</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/20210126-telegram-en-pavel-durov/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/20210126-telegram-en-pavel-durov/</guid>
      <description>Goodbye WhatsApp In 2020, WhatsApp reached the milestone of two billion users, which the company (owned by Facebook since 2014) said made them humbled and honored. But there was little humility to be seen in the new terms of service the messaging app announced barely a year later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Davie504 in Moscow</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/200215-davie504-in-moskou/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/200215-davie504-in-moskou/</guid>
      <description>Davie&amp;rsquo;s small tour through Moscow (2019, 3 m) is worth watching, but you can only see it on YouTube. From a year earlier is When you&amp;rsquo;re a bassist but you visited Russia once (2018, 2 m). Featuring ushanka, the Russian national anthem, сука блят, and vodka.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jokes about Russians and Russia</title>
      <link>/en/land-en-volk/200215-grappen-over-russen-en-rusland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/land-en-volk/200215-grappen-over-russen-en-rusland/</guid>
      <description>Trevor Noah: Vinyl Backwards From Some Languages Are Scary (2018).
Louis C.K: A Really Crazy Place About the time Louis C.K. went to Russia in his twenties. It was 1994.
‘Somebody told me that the Wall had just come down in the Soviet Union and that Russia was a really crazy place at the time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
