<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>LearnRussian.org on Rusland 1</title>
    <link>/en/trefwoorden/learnrussian.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in LearnRussian.org on Rusland 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/trefwoorden/learnrussian.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VERBS</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20240822-werkwoordenschat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20240822-werkwoordenschat/</guid>
      <description>Here is a selection of resources and channels you can use to do just that. Limited to the basic verbs, leaving out the special and more complex ones (verbs of motion, verbs on -ся, verbs with prepositions) for the most part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Past Tense</title>
      <link>/en/taal/200217-verleden-tijd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/200217-verleden-tijd/</guid>
      <description>Three Forms (or Actually Four) Masculine, feminine, and formal or plural: verbs in the past tense take on only three forms. Or actually four, but the form for оно (it) is rarely used. After all, an оно doesn’t (or didn’t) do much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First and Second Conjugation</title>
      <link>/en/taal/200216-eerste-en-tweede-vervoeging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/200216-eerste-en-tweede-vervoeging/</guid>
      <description>It is useful – and inevitable – to learn these conjugations. The same patterns recur frequently.
Learn Russian Verbs The series Глаголы (verbs) from LearnRussian.org teaches you verbs in a manageable set of five at a time. Conjugations and applications in sentences, along with short stories and the voice of Anastacia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vocabulary</title>
      <link>/en/taal/190422-woordenschat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/190422-woordenschat/</guid>
      <description>With love – here are clips (and resources) to help you learn Russian words and build your vocabulary.
Reading First Words Short words that are easy to follow, with pictures included. Да, нет, кот (yes, no, cat): if this is too simple, here is part 2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
