<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hard on Rusland 1</title>
    <link>/en/genres/hard/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hard on Rusland 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/genres/hard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Offret 3x</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20240519-offret-3x/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20240519-offret-3x/</guid>
      <description>Dark ‘Songs about the dark side of human nature,’ was once the description on Offret&amp;rsquo;s VK page – still visible in the headline of this interview (Idioteq, 2017). Nowadays, it has changed to: ‘black metal with dark synths and acoustic soundscapes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gospod – Holy Metal and the Seven Deadly Sins</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20210305-gospod_holy_metal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20210305-gospod_holy_metal/</guid>
      <description>Greed The Main Sins of Humanity (2021) contains seven tracks, which shouldn’t come as a surprise. Greed is the first, and it makes you want more.
The lyrics were not found online, but here they are, with спасибо (thanks) to Gospod.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WLVS – Mirages (Миражи) and the two before it</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20201229-wlvs-mirages/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20201229-wlvs-mirages/</guid>
      <description>Just in time for 2020 came Миражи, which makes for a good moment to look at a trilogy of their work. Unlike what’s usually done here, we’ll go from old to new.
Lost Kids From March 2019. With a cool video and a pro-life message (сейчас мы выбираем жить – now we choose to live), even for those who might feel lost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vuara – Less &amp; Without (Меньше Слов &amp; Без Людей)</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20201205-vuara-minder-zonder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20201205-vuara-minder-zonder/</guid>
      <description>Vuara is still young. Music videos are for later, and their repertoire is still limited. Just one album, but it weighs heavy enough for two: Свобода шума (Freedom of Noise, 2020). Here are two songs: one about less (words) and one about without (people).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supruga (Супруга) 3x</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20200802-supruga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20200802-supruga/</guid>
      <description>No one is safe After Хаос (chaos, 2019), the most recent album (an EP) is Никто не в безопасности (no one is safe, 2020). Only three tracks, with this as the final and title track. You can also listen on Spotify and Bandcamp, where the lyrics are also available for those who look closely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convince – Religion</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20200627-convince-religie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20200627-convince-religie/</guid>
      <description>Terror Strong words about (and mostly against) religion. It is террор (terror), and зло (evil). Also the кнут (knout, whip) that drives you into the pen (что отправит в загон). You will pray (ты будешь молиться) but will not be saved (не будешь спасён).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WLVS – Torn Apart (В клочья)</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20200214-wlvs-aan-stukken/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20200214-wlvs-aan-stukken/</guid>
      <description>Me and You В клочья is from Дотла: часть 1 (2016) and is more accessible than most. Despite everything, the short lyrics convey hope. Ты сможешь спасти остатки этой разодранной в клочья души: you can save the remnants of this torn-apart soul.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vólan – The Beginning (Начало)</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/190524_vo%CC%81lan-%D0%BD%D0%B0%D1%87%D0%B0%D0%BB%D0%BE/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/190524_vo%CC%81lan-%D0%BD%D0%B0%D1%87%D0%B0%D0%BB%D0%BE/</guid>
      <description>theater closed, actors dismissed,
I cannot retrieve what is lost.
the final act and the curtain falls,
farewell, world of illusions, I begin anew.
(Lyrics)
More Vólan (Moscow) on Bandcamp and VK.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
