<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Amazing Russian on Rusland 1</title>
    <link>/en/trefwoorden/amazing-russian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Amazing Russian on Rusland 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/trefwoorden/amazing-russian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VERBS</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20240822-werkwoordenschat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20240822-werkwoordenschat/</guid>
      <description>Here is a selection of resources and channels you can use to do just that. Limited to the basic verbs, leaving out the special and more complex ones (verbs of motion, verbs on -ся, verbs with prepositions) for the most part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SIXTH NOUN: LOCATIVE/PREPOSITIONAL</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20240601_zesde_naamval__locatief_prepositional/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20240601_zesde_naamval__locatief_prepositional/</guid>
      <description>Here (only) about usage; conjugations in a subsequent section, though you will inevitably encounter them below. Location The main use of the sixth noun is to designate a place - the name “locative” already indicates it, most other uses flow from it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perfective and imperfective</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20210406-perfectief_en_imperfectief/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20210406-perfectief_en_imperfectief/</guid>
      <description>Result or process Russian verbs are either perfective (совершенный вид, сов./св.) or imperfective (несовершенный вид, нес./нсв.) and thus form pairs. The first expresses result (a completed action), the second process, unfinished or repeated action. To compare with the difference between reading out and reading in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imperative Mood (Imperative)</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20210128-gebiedende-wijs-imperatief/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20210128-gebiedende-wijs-imperatief/</guid>
      <description>You need to know a few things to be able to do this in Russian. Take a look.
они-form To form the imperative mood in Russian, you start with the они (they) conjugation of the verb. Remove the ending and replace it with something else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fifth Case: Instrumental</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20210113-vijfde-naamval-instrumentalis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20210113-vijfde-naamval-instrumentalis/</guid>
      <description>Usage Professions We say: he works as a lawyer, or: he is a lawyer. Russian can do that without &amp;ldquo;as&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;is.&amp;rdquo; Кем он работает = what does he work as, what is his profession. Кто (who) in the instrumental case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ш and щ: Spot the Differences</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20201227-zoek-de-verschillen-sha-en-sshha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20201227-zoek-de-verschillen-sha-en-sshha/</guid>
      <description>Sound For what descriptions of sounds are worth: Wikipedia compares ш to ‘sh in shop’ and ‘ch in machine,’ but when it comes to щ, it hits a dead end: ‘Dutch has no words with this sound.’ The English Wikipedia entry for shcha/щ isn’t much help either: ‘it represents the voiceless alveolo-palatal fricative /ɕ(ː)/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian Adjectives (Прилагательные)</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20201219-russische-bijvoeglijk-naamwoorden/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20201219-russische-bijvoeglijk-naamwoorden/</guid>
      <description>Declensions Flexible First, you need to know how to decline them. Russian adjectives are flexible: they adapt to the gender and number of the noun they modify. New text, new idea, new morning, new plans: новый текст (m.), новая идея (f.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fourth Case: Accusative</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20201125-vierde-naamval-accusatief/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20201125-vierde-naamval-accusatief/</guid>
      <description>Usage Direct Object The fourth case, or accusative, is used when something happens to someone or something. In the sentence, it acts as the direct object. For example: &amp;ldquo;I buy a magazine, I read the newspaper.&amp;rdquo; Magazine and newspaper are direct objects (and take the accusative case) because they are being bought or read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian Calendar Words: Months and Days</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20201118-russische-kalenderwoorden-maanden-en-dagen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20201118-russische-kalenderwoorden-maanden-en-dagen/</guid>
      <description>January–December Let’s start with the months of the year. They&amp;rsquo;re not particularly exciting—no more interesting than the names you&amp;rsquo;re used to. The origins are the same: Roman gods and goddesses (January, March, May, June), words (February, April), emperors (July, August), and numbers (September through December).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Third Case: Dative</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20200818-derde-naamval-datief/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20200818-derde-naamval-datief/</guid>
      <description>Use дательный падеж when someone or something receives something. Here&amp;rsquo;s how and when to use it.
Usage You use дательный падеж in the following situations.
Indirect Object When something is given or directed at someone. Often, the recipient is a person, and the dative case takes over the role of &amp;ldquo;to&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family Name, First Name, and Patronymic (FIO) and Names in Russian</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20200722-familie-voor-en-vadersnaam-en-namen-in-het-russisch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20200722-familie-voor-en-vadersnaam-en-namen-in-het-russisch/</guid>
      <description>Learn more in What is отчество in Russian?! Abbreviation ФИО in Russian (Ru-Land Club, 2017, 9 m) and Basic guide to Russian names | Name, Last Name &amp;amp; Patronymic in Russian (Daria Mikhay, 2017, 5 m).
Son or daughter The отчество (óhtjestva) is slightly different for a son than for a daughter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nominative Case: именительный падеж</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20200417-eerste-naamval-nominatief/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20200417-eerste-naamval-nominatief/</guid>
      <description>What or who The nominative case is the unmodified or default form of a word. If nothing is being done to it in the sentence, you don’t need to do anything either.*)
This is my car, the book is thick: машина and книга stay as they are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Pronouns</title>
      <link>/en/taal/200224-persoonlijk-voornaamwoord/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/200224-persoonlijk-voornaamwoord/</guid>
      <description>The forms of the second and fourth cases (genitive and accusative) are even identical.
именительный родительный дательный винительный творительный предложный я меня мне меня мной (обо) мне ты тебя тебе тебя тобой (о) тебе он/оно его ему его им (о) нём она её ей её ей (о) ней мы нас нам нас нами (о) нас вы вас вам вас вами (о) вас они их им их ими (о) них Russian Personal Pronouns – Nominative Case (Learn Russian Now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To have, to have, to have</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20200219-hebben/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20200219-hebben/</guid>
      <description>у &amp;hellip; есть Literally, a Russian doesn’t say &amp;ldquo;I have,&amp;rdquo; but rather &amp;ldquo;by me is.&amp;rdquo; For that &amp;ldquo;by,&amp;rdquo; you use у, &amp;ldquo;is&amp;rdquo; becomes есть, and in between comes the personal pronoun in the genitive (second case). This turns я (I) into меня.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telling Time in Russian</title>
      <link>/en/taal/200218-klokkijken/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/200218-klokkijken/</guid>
      <description>First Half-Hour 12 minutes past 3, for a Russian, is 12 minutes from the fourth. That last part (from the fourth) requires two steps. From четыре (four), you make четвёртый (fourth). To say &amp;lsquo;from the&amp;rsquo;, you apply the second case (genitive) to четвёртый, resulting in четвёртого – from the fourth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First and Second Conjugation</title>
      <link>/en/taal/200216-eerste-en-tweede-vervoeging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/200216-eerste-en-tweede-vervoeging/</guid>
      <description>It is useful – and inevitable – to learn these conjugations. The same patterns recur frequently.
Learn Russian Verbs The series Глаголы (verbs) from LearnRussian.org teaches you verbs in a manageable set of five at a time. Conjugations and applications in sentences, along with short stories and the voice of Anastacia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Learn Russian?</title>
      <link>/en/taal/190612-waarom-russisch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/190612-waarom-russisch/</guid>
      <description>Plus everything listed below.
Why Study Russian? (Amazing Russian, 2016, 8 m)
Why Learn Russian? – 5 Reasons (Real Russian Club, 2018, 4 m)
Why You Should Learn Russian Language (Be Fluent in Russian, 2018, 8 m)
From the same channel:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masculine, Feminine, Neuter</title>
      <link>/en/taal/190611-mannelijk-vrouwelijk-onzijdig/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/190611-mannelijk-vrouwelijk-onzijdig/</guid>
      <description>Exceptions For every rule, there’s an exception. имя (name) and время (time) are neuter, кофе (coffee) is masculine, and there are more examples like these. And if a word ends in ь (мягкий знак, the soft sign), it can be either masculine or feminine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vocabulary</title>
      <link>/en/taal/190422-woordenschat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/190422-woordenschat/</guid>
      <description>With love – here are clips (and resources) to help you learn Russian words and build your vocabulary.
Reading First Words Short words that are easy to follow, with pictures included. Да, нет, кот (yes, no, cat): if this is too simple, here is part 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gluing Sounds</title>
      <link>/en/taal/190421-klanken-plakken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/190421-klanken-plakken/</guid>
      <description>From Letters to Words The first step in Russian – learning the alphabet – is already a big step forward. Once you know the letters and their sounds, you can immediately read and pronounce a lot. You just glue the sounds together and try not to stumble.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
