<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>anti on Rusland 1</title>
    <link>/en/trefwoorden/anti/</link>
    <description>Recent content in anti on Rusland 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/trefwoorden/anti/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Индульгенция – Feministka</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20201121-indulgencia-feministka/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20201121-indulgencia-feministka/</guid>
      <description>Explained in Панк-католицизм группы «Индульгенция», the punk Catholicism of the band Indulgencia (Nihilist.li, 2017).
Oegarelaja The language used to address the feminist in the song isn’t exactly Christian. To start, she’s called угорелая (oegarelaja), which loosely translates to &amp;ldquo;crazy.&amp;rdquo; She’s also такая тупая (so dumb), like the whole world (как весь этот мир), and такая кривая (so crooked, skewed, wrong), like everyone around her (как все вокруг).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convince – Religion</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/20200627-convince-religie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/20200627-convince-religie/</guid>
      <description>Terror Strong words about (and mostly against) religion. It is террор (terror), and зло (evil). Also the кнут (knout, whip) that drives you into the pen (что отправит в загон). You will pray (ты будешь молиться) but will not be saved (не будешь спасён).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Би-2 – Hipster</title>
      <link>/en/muziek/190421-%D0%B1%D0%B8-2hipster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/muziek/190421-%D0%B1%D0%B8-2hipster/</guid>
      <description>London vibes Узкие джинсы, майка с принтом = skinny jeans and a shirt with a print. This rhymes with В целом не важно что будет потом: generally, it doesn’t matter what comes after. Лечь на дно (lit.: lie on the bottom) with your London music (вместе с музыкой Лондона), all gone by (всё прошло) and out of style (всё такое не модное).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
