<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anna Cher on Rusland 1</title>
    <link>/en/trefwoorden/anna-cher/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Anna Cher on Rusland 1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/trefwoorden/anna-cher/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learning Russian with News</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20240622_russisch_leren_met_nieuws/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20240622_russisch_leren_met_nieuws/</guid>
      <description>Series Yaroslava Russian has quite a range. From Prigozhin&amp;rsquo;s Plane Crash (2023, 29 m) to a Documented Alien (2024, 27 m). Collected in a playlist, including.
7 years in jail for anti-war price tag protest (2023, 23 m) New Argentinian president deports all Russians from Argentina (2023, 23 m) Russian President resigns in New Year&amp;rsquo;s night (2024, 55 m) Russia might have a new candidate for president (2024, 36 m) The biggest meteor in 100 years Explodes in Chelyabinsk, Russia (2024, 30 m) Victory Day | Germany&amp;rsquo;s Surrender in WWII (2024, 33 m) Learn Russian with News | Why books in Russia are being censored (2024, 24 m) Article on realnoevremya.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Russian with Interviews</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20210213-russisch-leren-met-interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20210213-russisch-leren-met-interviews/</guid>
      <description>Viktor Tsoi The series of interviews by Boost Your Russian is modest in scope but features great names, with bilingual subtitles. For instance, Viktor Tsoi (or Цой), shortly after a viewing of the film Игла (The Needle, 1988). Watch it on YouTube, starring Shocking Blue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Russian Calendar Words: Months and Days</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20201118-russische-kalenderwoorden-maanden-en-dagen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20201118-russische-kalenderwoorden-maanden-en-dagen/</guid>
      <description>January–December Let’s start with the months of the year. They&amp;rsquo;re not particularly exciting—no more interesting than the names you&amp;rsquo;re used to. The origins are the same: Roman gods and goddesses (January, March, May, June), words (February, April), emperors (July, August), and numbers (September through December).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Russian with Vladimir Putin (2/2)</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20200515-leer-russisch-met-poetin-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20200515-leer-russisch-met-poetin-2/</guid>
      <description>With a questioner who might also work for a school newspaper and a rather admiring boyish look. Anna introduces it with: “an interview with a person about whom everyone seems to have an opinion, positive or negative.” And concludes with: “and we will refrain from any political comments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second Case: Genitive</title>
      <link>/en/taal/20200419-tweede-naamval-genitief/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/20200419-tweede-naamval-genitief/</guid>
      <description>Usage Of the The genitive is a &amp;lsquo;of the&amp;rsquo; (or &amp;lsquo;of the&amp;rsquo;) case. Where Dutch uses compound words (schoonheidssalon, wereldkampioenschap) and English uses separate words (beauty salon, world championship), Russian uses the second case for such things. Thus, you get салон красоты (salon of beauty) and чемпионат мира (championship of the world).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masculine, Feminine, Neuter</title>
      <link>/en/taal/190611-mannelijk-vrouwelijk-onzijdig/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/taal/190611-mannelijk-vrouwelijk-onzijdig/</guid>
      <description>Exceptions For every rule, there’s an exception. имя (name) and время (time) are neuter, кофе (coffee) is masculine, and there are more examples like these. And if a word ends in ь (мягкий знак, the soft sign), it can be either masculine or feminine.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
